<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kira McLean</title>
    <link>https://kiramclean.com</link>
    <description>Kira's thoughts and guides on tech, life, and meaning.</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 18:37:48 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kiramclean.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Morphy v0.0</generator>
    <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      <item>
        <title>Becoming A Software Developer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I get asked a lot for advice on becoming a software developer. I didn't study anything related to software in university, but now it's what I do for a living. I also spent about 3.5 years mentoring with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lighthouselabs.ca&quot;&gt;Lighthouse Labs&lt;/a&gt;, a local web development bootcamp, and watched (and would like to believe at least in some cases, helped) hundreds of people of every age from wildly diverse backgrounds get jobs as software developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my advice for people with no technical experience who want to land their first job writing software. It's based on my experience as both a person who did it myself and as a mentor to other people who did it. There's no single right way to go about this, and no matter how you do it's a lot of work. But these are some things that have worked for other people, myself included. These suggestions are arranged roughly in order, but of course many overlap and kind of happen at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Know what you're getting yourself into&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software engineering is nothing like I expected it to be. All the hard parts involve dealing with people. Part of my original motivation for choosing a career in software was thinking I wouldn't have to deal much with people. I wasn't very good at it and didn't enjoy it, but my fantasy of just sitting in front of my computer all day and watching my bank account fill up was totally delusional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reality of writing code for a living, in my experience, includes dealing with a lot of office politics, entitled middle managers, stressed out co-workers, and yes, condescencion and occasional harassment (especially if you're not male). I find the culture of the tech industry generally toxic and abusive and it has very nearly broken my spirit on multiple occasions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You won't be alone dealing with this. Your co-workers and countless people across the industry share the experience. And it is ultimately bearable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't say this to discourage anyone from getting into software, but just to highlight that the stuff you hear from recruiters is bullshit. It's not all free trips and fancy perks and big paycheques. It is those things, sure, but the reality is much less glamorous than they make it sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a software developer means getting paid to solve other people's problems. The rest is fluff. This makes it a solid career path, though, because other people have a lot of problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is still an empowering and lucrative career. Despite my generally negative view of the industry, I still highly recommend and help people into a career in software regularly. Most individual software developers, like most people, are genuine and kind. And I can't speak to problems in other industries first hand, but I gather most high-paying, male-dominated industries are pretty similar anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Meet lots of people&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was referred to three of the four programming jobs I've had so far through friends. I made friends with those people who were already programmers at meetups. I didn't ask them to get me a job, but a lot of companies are pretty much always looking for new software engineers, so when your friend hears you're looking for that kind of job, they can bring it up at work. I still did interviews, but it makes an enormous difference when someone the boss already knows and trusts can vouch for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A word on meeting strangers. I, like many people who are into nerd things like software, am the most introverted person I know. I found hanging out in groups of new people excruciating at first, but honestly learning how to not be awkward around strangers is just as important as learning how to code if you want to do well in your career. I just went to the meetups and stood off to the side, awkwardly making eye contact with a few random people. Eventually a friendly extrovert would come up and initiate a conversation, and before I knew it I could hold my own in a crowd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out meetups for programming languages you're interested in, or if there aren't those kinds of groups where you live, join online communities. Most programming languages have a slack or discord server where people hang out, and in my experience people are usually very welcoming and kind to newbies (at least in the Ruby, Elixir, and Clojure communities; all of which I highly recommend).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Learn how to code, in public&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without any formal education in software development, you have to offer something else to prove you actually know how to write code. I did this by building a bunch of crappy side projects. The very first thing I ever did was replicate the Google landing page with HTML and CSS. The first actual app I made was a blackjack game with Sinatra. I also made Twitter and Reddit clones with Rails, and little browser games like Pacman with different JavaScript frameworks. Some of that code still exists in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kmclean-old&quot;&gt;GitHub graveyard&lt;/a&gt; if you want to see what I mean by crappy. Other common toy projects include link shorteners, photo galleries, e-commerce stores, time trackers, or clones of whatever software you normally use, like spreadsheets, workflow management, calendars, etc. The possibilities are endless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look for tutorials online that walk through how to build the kinds of things you're interested in. If you don't know where to start, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theodinproject.com&quot;&gt;The Odin Project&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.org&quot;&gt;Free Code Camp&lt;/a&gt; are two free programs that offer very realistic learning roadmaps. I did parts of both of those but never finished either. I also did several free courses on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/browse/computer-science&quot;&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/course/subject/computer-science&quot;&gt;edX&lt;/a&gt;, which are both amazing but you have to be careful not to end up in a rabbit hole. Those two mostly have actual university courses, which are super interesting, but not very relevant to things you'll do in a real job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your goal is to get from nothing to making money as a developer as fast as possible I recommend sticking to a more targeted learning roadmap like the two above. There are also countless paid ones which vary wildly in price and quality. Be weary about shelling out huge amounts of money for bootcamps. I did pay for a few months of &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchschool.com&quot;&gt;Launch School&lt;/a&gt; (which at the time was called &amp;quot;Tea Leaf Academy&amp;quot;), and it was the best career move I ever made. I highly recommend them because they're in a sweet spot of offering a robust and relevant curriculum without costing a fortune. It's not free ($200/month), but a few hundred dollars is a very small investment in the scheme of your career. Apparently they also offer a deferred payment option now, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The career-oriented bootcamps will also teach you loads of useful practical things they don't teach in the free university courses, like version control (git), testing, and how to collaborate with other developers on one project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me 6 months of studying, meeting people, and building crappy software full time before I got my first internship. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lighthouselabs.ca/student-outcomes&quot;&gt;95% of Lighthouse Labs graduates&lt;/a&gt; are employed as software developers in that timeframe. Launch School delivers &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchschool.com/results&quot;&gt;impressive, concrete results&lt;/a&gt; for many of their students, too. I never finished most of the courses or programs I started. I funded that time off by living like a peasant on money I made running one of those student painting businesses the previous summer. Learning to code can feel like a slog at times, but just stick with it and you're very likely to be among the vast majority who succeed at this self-educated developer thing. It is a totally achievable and realistic goal and you're in good company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than doing free online courses and building apps from tutorials, other ways I learned in public during this time included blogging about my learning journey, making myself a portfolio website to showcase my little projects, and volunteering with some local tech communities. Do what works for you, but focus on ending up with at least a few medium sized projects you can show someone to prove you know how to make software that works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Learn best practices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A surprising number of experienced developers still write really horrible code. Spend some time learning about software design and software engineering best practices to avoid becoming one of them. How you do that depends a lot on how you learn. (BTW, you should figure that out before you embark upon a journey of self-re-education for a career change). I absorb a lot from reading and prefer to learn by studying theory over trial and error, so reading and watching talks works really well for me. YMMV and you do ultimately just need experience to really get this stuff, but you don't have to start from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read &amp;quot;The Pragmatic Programmer&amp;quot; by Dave Thomas and Andrew Hunt, and anything by Sandi Metz. Watch Rich Hickey's talks, especially &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infoq.com/presentations/Simple-Made-Easy/&quot;&gt;Simple Made Easy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;, and Sarah Mei's &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brightonruby.com/2017/livable-code-sarah-mei/&quot;&gt;Livable Code&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;. Other classics include Eric Evans' &amp;quot;Domain Driven Design&amp;quot; and Martin Fowler's &amp;quot;Refactoring&amp;quot;. There are countless others and everyone has their opinion about what should be included in the software engineering canon, but these are my recommendations. They'll provide a solid foundation and ample fodder for further reading and watching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pour your heart out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you can write code that mostly works, start looking for a job. Put the word out that you're seeking your first role writing software. Hopefully one of your programmer friends will know about an open position, but you can still apply to random jobs on the internet, too. This has a very low success rate, but it's possible. I got one of my four jobs by firing my resume into the abyss. I included a very long and heartfelt cover letter about how I loved programming so much and really wanted to work for this specific company (which I did), and how I learn fast and really believed I could do the job if they'd give me a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It worked. The hiring manager said my letter caught his attention. I had one year of experience at that time and had never worked remotely before, but I got the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't be afraid to be authentic. Don't lie and say you know more than you do, but don't sell yourself short, either. Bootstrapping a career in software is no small feat and there are many teams out there who would love to hire the kinds of self-starting fast learners who do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Don't be too picky (at first!)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reality is that your first job or two will probably be pretty crappy and underpaid. At this point you're trying to convince someone to take a chance on you, and it's a trade off between your dignity and your future career. In the very beginning, you should prioritize gaining experience over almost everything else. Obviously never put up with anything you're uncomfortable with, but if you can stick it out it's worth setting the bar pretty low just to get your first few months of real job experience, IMHO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lucked out and worked with the most amazing team in the world for my first job as a developer, but I discovered from the students I mentored that that is very much not the norm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are pros and cons to every kind of company, so don't worry too much about finding the perfect fit right away. Focus on gaining experience at first so you can have the freedom to focus on finding the perfect fit later. I've worked with a few different kinds of companies and there are pros and cons no matter where you go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big corporations usually have a lot of experienced developers and lethargic processes, so there's more opportunity to take your time and get help from people more advanced than you. The pressure is often pretty low because people have such low expectations for new developers, which honestly is fair. You have a lot of room to screw up because you're such a tiny cog in a massive machine. The downsides depend on your personality. For me it was that I find most large tech companies to be evil and didn't like the soul-crushing feeling of helping to build something I hated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Startups usually have fewer people available to be mentors, but more opportunity to take on disproportionate responsibility for your level, which can be an amazing learning experience in a different way. You also have a lot of room to screw up, but it's more because your screw ups just blend in with the overall culture of moving fast and breaking things. I now believe that's a ridiculous way to run a business, but when there's widespread acceptance of breaking even important things, you have a lot freedom to experiment and learn by trial and error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Be a good student&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, once you finally land your first job, be a good student. Treat your first year or two on the job like paid education, not your chance to go in and show everyone how it's done. You know way less than you think, and you have no idea what it takes to build functioning software systems, let alone to deploy or maintain them. Always be humble and eager to learn. Soak up every minute of attention you get from more experienced developers around you and learn from them. Not everything they say is wise or true, but pay attention and copy the things that work whilst ignoring the things that clearly don't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to ask good questions. Don't be afraid to ask for help, but before you do, at least try to figure out the problem yourself. Write down what you tried, and explain why you're surprised your attempt didn't work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are certain things you can only really learn from experience on a real world project, so see what opportunities there are to learn those things, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;securing and backing up actual important customer data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deploying a huge app with no downtime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactoring large, messy, legacy codebases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adding new features to large, messy, legacy codebases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixing obscure bugs with no instructions to reproduce them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are just a few examples of things you won't run into on your little demo projects. Pay attention to the problems you're dealing with at work that you don't run into on side projects and learn how to fix those. That's your pathway to levelling up. Most importantly, never stop learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;That's all&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software development is a great career. It's allowed me to be financially independent and stable, travel the world, meet cool people, and lots more. My path won't work for everyone. There are as many different ways to become a software developer as there are people, but I've seen countless aspiring software engineers go through their own journeys and many of them touch on these points, so see how they fit in to your own path. And let me know how it goes 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://kiramclean.com/blog/becoming-a-software-developer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kiramclean.com/blog/becoming-a-software-developer/</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What I Use Now Instead Of Google</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I made a goal for myself in January 2020 to stop using Google products by the end of the year. That might sound like way too generous a timeline, but Google owned pretty much all of my data at that point, so it was a fairly large project. Plus I'm a slow and steady kind of person. I know if I give myself a generous enough timeline I can accomplish even things that seem too hard for me at first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;First, Why&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I got into programming about 5 years ago, I kept hearing all these bad things about Google and how horrible of a company it is from other tech people. It always seemed a bit exaggerated to me, but the evidence has been piling up over the years. Learning about &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/google-is-helping-the-pentagon-build-ai-for-drones-1823464533&quot;&gt;their involvement&lt;/a&gt; with the US military's &lt;a href=&quot;https://dodcio.defense.gov/Portals/0/Documents/Project%20Maven%20DSD%20Memo%2020170425.pdf&quot;&gt;Algorithmic Warfare Cross-Functional Team (Project Maven)&lt;/a&gt; was the last straw for me &lt;sup id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href= &quot;https://kiramclean.com/blog/what-i-use-now-instead-of-google/#footnote-1-text&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but even before I learned about that I was pretty uncomfortable with a lot of what I heard. In Google's defence they eventually did &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20210101083904/https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/01/technology/google-pentagon-project-maven.html&quot;&gt;pull out of the project&lt;/a&gt; after &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20201231204850/https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/04/technology/google-letter-ceo-pentagon-project.html&quot;&gt;massive backlash by thousands of employees&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I'm pretty convinced now that their continued existence is a catastrophe not only for public safety, but also for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/recode/2020/1/3/21030688/google-amazon-ai-oil-gas&quot;&gt;the environment&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/01/technology/google-walkout-sexual-harassment.html&quot;&gt;gender equity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.telegraph.co.uk/technology/google/9739039/Googles-tax-avoidance-is-called-capitalism-says-chairman-Eric-Schmidt.html&quot;&gt;the economy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/jgexe8/google-fired-an-engineer-who-wrote-code-telling-googlers-they-had-a-right-to-organize&quot;&gt;fair labour practices&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stallman.org/google.html#surveillance&quot;&gt;privacy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41562-020-00954-0&quot;&gt;journalism&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judiciary.senate.gov/download/epstein-testimony&quot;&gt;democracy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2018/4/3/17168256/google-racism-algorithms-technology&quot;&gt;race relations&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/big-tech-out-of-control-capitalism-and-the-end-of-civilization/&quot;&gt;project of civilization itself&lt;/a&gt;. But anyway, the point of this post isn't to motivate you to also quit Google. I'll tell you how I really feel some other time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of this post is about the tools and services I replaced all the Google things with. I did mostly accomplish my goal, with a few caveats which I describe in the relevant sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Replacements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the short version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GMail → &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/signup&quot;&gt;ProtonMail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chrome → &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/developer/&quot;&gt;Firefox developer edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google search → &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/&quot;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Drive → &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sync.com/&quot;&gt;Sync&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/b2/cloud-storage.html&quot;&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google DNS → &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cloudflare.com/announcing-1111/&quot;&gt;Cloudflare DNS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maps → Apple maps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YouTube → Netflix, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/&quot;&gt;TED talks&lt;/a&gt;, conference archives, and still a little YouTube (anonymously in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/multi-account-containers/&quot;&gt;Firefox container&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Analytics → &lt;a href=&quot;https://usefathom.com/&quot;&gt;Fathom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything else (calendar, reminders, photos, docs, video chat, news feeds) → &lt;a href=&quot;https://nextcloud.com/signup/&quot;&gt;Nextcloud&lt;/a&gt;, running &lt;a href=&quot;https://kiramclean.com/blog/how-to-set-up-your-own-nextcloud-server/&quot;&gt;on my own instance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here's the long version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;GMail → &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/signup&quot;&gt;ProtonMail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ProtonMail has free accounts, but I pay for the lowest level that allows use of a custom domain with it (€48/year) so I don't have to change my email address ever again if I want to switch providers. It was quite a pain to change my email address all over the place, but I started in May and just did it slowly over time. I highly recommend decoupling your email address from your email provider if you're considering switching. First of all an email from a custom domain seems more, not less, serious than a gmail address to most people. But the main reason is just so you don't have to change your email address ever again if (when) you want to switch to some newer, better email provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set up forwarding from my old GMail account to my new email address then filtered my mail for anything sent to the old address. If it was someone or some place I wanted to continue hearing from, I updated my email address with them. If not I unsubscribed. This turned out to be a wonderful opportunity to purge my newsletter and other email subscriptions. Also I'm happy to report most companies are now (finally) respecting unsubscribe requests. Two (looking at you Geektastic and Rakuten) continued to spam me after I requested they stop, so now I filter out all their mail as spam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chrome → Firefox developer edition&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I primarily use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/developer/&quot;&gt;Firefox developer edition&lt;/a&gt; now for my browser, including for work. The developer tools are just as good as Chrome's for the kind of work I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some web apps that literally or effectively only work in Chrome, which ironically perfectly illustrates the impetus for this whole undertaking. For those I use this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium#downloads&quot;&gt;ungoogled Chromium&lt;/a&gt; browser, installed via homebrew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still have Chrome installed on my computer because I need it for some work things. We use chromedriver for some integration tests and it wasn't trivially easy to trick it into using my Chromium installation instead of looking for Chrome. Replacing chromedriver is a headache, and also not my call to make at work. But it's also not really the point for me. If Google was reduced to a browser that developers can easily launch and control programmatically, I'd be satisfied. I don't use it for anything other than running automated tests at work now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Google search → &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/&quot;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mostly love DuckDuckGo, but there are certain categories of searches where Google returns better results. DuckDuckGo doesn't seem to return many results from forums (like stack overflow or other stack exchange sites), which is where there the answers to a lot of my questions are, unfortunately. So I still use Google Search sometimes, but I do it in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/multi-account-containers/&quot;&gt;Firefox container&lt;/a&gt; without being logged in to a Google account, which at least helps to avoid some of Google's incessant stalking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DuckDuckGo does seem to return better results when the answer is an image, video, or regular web page, which is cool, and I suspect means it would be a perfectly fine replacement for most people. For example this blog is easier to find via DuckDuckGo than Google, which is impressive because I share a name with a small-time TV celebrity who typically dominates search results. We even look sort of similar, it's wild.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Google Drive → &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sync.com/&quot;&gt;Sync&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/b2/cloud-storage.html&quot;&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Sync to make my most used files available anywhere, and I've started moving a huge backlog of documents and notes I don't need to access often but don't want to throw away to Backblaze for longer term storage, just because it's cheaper. So far I just use their web UI to upload things in bulk and browse my files, but I'm looking into ways to do that more efficiently. I really need to de-clutter my digital life. I'm a major hoarder when it comes to digital files. I have scarcely deleted a document in the last 10 years, it's getting a bit ridiculous. But that's a goal for another year 🙂. For now I'm just putting all those files I don't really need to access but don't want to throw away in Backblaze to deal with later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between Sync and Backblaze I got 15GB of free storage, which is plenty for now, though as I move more and more or my scattered files over I'll have to start paying. Backblaze offers some of the cheapest object storage there is, at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DNS → Cloudflare DNS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to use Google's DNS servers (8.8.8.8 and 8.8.4.4), now I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cloudflare.com/announcing-1111/&quot;&gt;Cloudflare's&lt;/a&gt; (1.1.1.1 and 1.0.0.1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Maps, YouTube&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These ones are harder to replace. I use Apple maps now most of the time, but I still use Waze (which was acquired by Google) for directions sometimes if I'm driving somewhere. For media I mostly watch Netflix, but I also watch a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/&quot;&gt;TED talks&lt;/a&gt;. I used to also watch conference videos on YouTube. Now I check conference websites for those, and a lot of them have the recordings, although they're often hosted on YouTube anyway. And I also do still use YouTube sometimes, mostly for home workout videos, but also anonymously in an isolated container.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Analytics → &lt;a href=&quot;https://usefathom.com/&quot;&gt;Fathom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been a while since I used Google Analytics, but I wanted to set up a basic hit counter for this blog and found Fathom. They provide simple privacy-focused analytics that work well enough for me. One really useful feature they have that I consider necessary now is being able to log analytics with a custom domain. Without this, visitors using ad-blockers don't get counted, which most estimates figure is now something like 40% of people, and probably more among tech-type people, like the ones most likely to find this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried Cloudflare's new server-side analytics for a month, but the data didn't make as much sense (it showed the overwhelming number of visits to my homepage, even though the other analytics I had set up showed them going to one post that did well on Hacker News, which makes way more sense). Anyway, the numbers didn't seem to add up. I guess to be fair I &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kiraemclean/status/1340530206516387840&quot;&gt;don't quite understand&lt;/a&gt; how Fathom's numbers add up yet either, but their support has been helpful checking it out with me to try to help me reach some interpretation that makes sense. Fathom's dashboard is really simple, at least, which I like because it's easy to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Calendar, reminders, photos, docs, video chat, news feeds → &lt;a href=&quot;https://nextcloud.com/signup/&quot;&gt;Nextcloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For everything else I use Nextcloud now. I &lt;a href=&quot;https://kiramclean.com/blog/how-to-set-up-your-own-nextcloud-server/&quot;&gt;run my own instance&lt;/a&gt; of it, but there are lots of providers where you can just sign up for a simple account like anything else if you're not an insufferable nerd who enjoys maintaining servers, like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where I have another caveat to mention. I haven't migrated all of my photos off of Google Photos yet because I have about 50,000 of them and it's just a really slow process. I estimated it would take me something like 70 hours to move them all manually, so I'm looking into better ways to do it. I'm confident I can find or maybe build something easier than manually downloading and uploading 50k files in less than 70 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nextcloud does the job of automatically syncing photos from my phone, though, which is all I needed to be able to delete Google Photos from my devices. I'm not sure I'll actually stick with Nextcloud for photos in the long run. The gallery is a bit lacking. It looks like &lt;a href=&quot;https://piwigo.org/get-piwigo&quot;&gt;Piwigo&lt;/a&gt; might be a good alternative. Either way, I'm actually storing my photos in Backblaze, so I'll continue looking around for a different client for a bucket full of photos next year as I work on slowly culling my photos collection and migrating it to a new home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Total Cost&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like I've won a lot by doing all this. I own my data now, so Google can't &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/google-users-locked-out-after-years-2020-10&quot;&gt;arbitrarily take it away from me&lt;/a&gt;, which gives me peace of mind. I'm no longer part of their ad ecosystem, being tracked all around the internet and having my attention sold to the highest bidder. And I also feel good about &amp;quot;voting with my feet&amp;quot;, so to speak. The fewer people use Google's free products, the lower their ability to sustain their unethical business model based on selling mass surveillance data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I also lost some. Specifically a few hundred dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting paid and paying for things in multiple currencies is the bane of my financial existence, but overall the final total comes out to something like CAD$400/year (roughly $300), broken down like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ProtonMail - €48/year (CAD$75)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom domains (for email and my cloud) - $19.74/year (CAD$25)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linode server (for my Nextcloud instance) - $84/year (CAD$105)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carbon offsets - CAD$21/year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fathom analytics - $140/year (CAD$180)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, $140 of the total is for Fathom analytics, which an average person probably doesn't need. Without that it comes closer to about $160, which I think is a fair price to pay for privacy, freedom, and ownership. I'm also not paying anything for storage yet, though, so I expect this to cost more next year once I finally get all my photos and archives migrated to Backblaze or whatever I end up using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should also emphasize it's entirely possible to switch off of Google to free alternatives. All the services I use have free tiers which are quite generous and most likely plenty for an average user. I do think people who can afford to should support independent software companies so they can run sustainable businesses off the money their customers give them and not off ad revenue, but when money is tight there are still lots of options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I got over the initial mental hurdle of expecting everything to be free or as cheap as possible, it seemed totally reasonable to me to pay that much for all I'm getting. What made it click for me is that all those things aren't actually free. Google sells our information and our attention to the highest bidder to generate profit for themselves, then they don't share any of it with us, despite the fact that their entire business model couldn't even exist if we all just refused to fuel it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I'm just dreaming waiting for the day Google realizes the error of its ways and starts running an ethical business, but that doesn't mean it's not worth taking a stand in the meantime. Individually refusing to fuel the databases and algorithms Google profits from is one tiny thing it's totally possible to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: A lot of people in the comments have pointed out that it takes a lot more than this to actually escape Google's reach, which is true. My comment above that I'm &amp;quot;no longer part of Google's ad ecosystem&amp;quot; is an overstatement. As &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25654222#25655515&quot;&gt;one commenter&lt;/a&gt; put it, &amp;quot;Google will still track much of what you do online. The internet is rotten with linked media, amp pages, blogs, and ads hosted on Google servers.&amp;quot; They're right, but that doesn't mean none of this has any impact. I find the de-googling community can be too defeatist and purist at times, but perhaps I swing too far the other direction here. I don't want to minimize the amount of effort it takes to truly become Google-free, but I also want to encourage and inspire average people to make these changes, which requires taking a more pragmatic approach.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discuss this post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25654222&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/kiraemclean/what-i-use-now-instead-of-google-56lf&quot;&gt;Dev.to&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/degoogle/comments/krexp7/i_spent_2020_replacing_all_the_google_things_in/&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small id=&quot;footnote-1-text&quot;&gt;1. That previous link goes to a memo saying that the primary purpose of the project is &amp;quot;to field technology to augment or automate Processing, Exploitation, and Dissemination (PED) for tactical Unmanned Aerial System (UAS)&amp;quot;, which means making AI for drones so they can better target humans and other &amp;quot;targets&amp;quot;. That really bothers me. &lt;a href=&quot;https://kiramclean.com/blog/what-i-use-now-instead-of-google/#footnote-1&quot;&gt;↵&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 5 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://kiramclean.com/blog/what-i-use-now-instead-of-google/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kiramclean.com/blog/what-i-use-now-instead-of-google/</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>2020 Year In Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I'm really excited that 2020 is over! This was the hardest year of my life so far. It was also the first one that was worse and not better than all the previous ones, which I'm really hoping is not a new trend. When I thought about it a bit I realized I still did a lot of cool things and learned a lot this year though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They're arranged roughly in order of least to most personal, so if you finish one section and thought &amp;quot;wow, that was a bit of an overshare, Kira&amp;quot;, then – fair warning – you might not want to continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I'm really proud of that I did this year is &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; get the cable situation behind my desk under control. I'll take whatever wins I can get right now, so I'm counting this as a big one. Here's what it looks like before and after:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://kiramclean.com/assets/images/2020-in-review/desk-before.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kira's desk before -- messy&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;My desk before figuring out a cable management solution. 😫&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://kiramclean.com/assets/images/2020-in-review/desk-after.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kira's desk after -- so nice&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;My desk after organizing everything underneath. So much nicer ☺️&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I moved this year, which gave my the perfect opportunity because I had to take everything off my desk anyway. I knew I had to do it then or else wait until the next time everything was off my desk for some reason. I just used some duct tape, large binder clips with washers so the screws would hold, and these aluminium hooks I found at the dollar store. I made a harness for my power strip out of the duct tape and screwed it and the other things into the bottom of the desk. I borrowed a drill from my landlord and already had the tape, so it all cost me about $10. This is what it looks like underneath:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kiramclean.com/assets/images/2020-in-review/desk-underneath.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Underneath my desk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this new apartment I had space for my bookshelf next to my desk, so that box on the bottom shelf in the &amp;quot;after&amp;quot; picture has my router and modem in it. It's so much better to not be kicking cables all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Puzzle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of celebrating wins, no matter how small, I'm counting this as one, too: I finished a big puzzle! I needed to find a lot of new hobbies that don't involve screens this year, so I bought a puzzle. It turns out it was pretty hard on my neck looking down for long periods, so I'm not sure if I'll do any more, but I really liked having something to keep my hands busy while I thought about other stuff or talked on the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kiramclean.com/assets/images/2020-in-review/puzzle-2020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My completed puzzle in 2020&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Remote Community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One silver lining of the pandemic is that it has made it really easy to connect with new people I never would have met before. The communities I participate in only on my computer have become a really important part of my life. A couple are religious (or ex-religious) communities that I found through my spiritual pursuits. I've been able to find and connect with people with really interesting and eye-opening perspectives that I don't think I would have ever met in real life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also signed up for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://indyhall.org/athome/&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;virtual&amp;quot; co-working community&lt;/a&gt; a couple of months ago and it's been a really great way to add some structure to my days, which otherwise all feel like a giant blur. It's mostly a bunch of other self-employed people who already had this great community before the pandemic and moved it online once it became obvious there's no end in sight. I'm looking forward to finding creative ways to keep in touch with all the cool new people I've met on the internet this year. It seems like it should be really compatible with my non-pandemic-time semi-nomadic lifestyle, so that's exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work is still going well for me. I've been very lucky to be able to continue working throughout the pandemic and I still love the team I work with. We have some of the usual issues software teams do, but overall the people I work with are genuinely kind and talented, which it seems is a lot to ask in the tech industry these days. They're easy to get along with and approach work and life the same way I do – not too seriously and with priorities straight. There were a few days I was just too sad and broken to work and everyone was very supportive, understanding, and helpful. All employers say they care about their staff, but this is the first place I've worked where I think that's actually true. I plan on continuing with this team for now, at least through next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been spending Friday afternoons mentoring at a local web development bootcamp, Lighthouse Labs, for a few years now, but this year I decided to stop. Because of the pandemic everything moved online, which partly contributed to my decision. They did a really good job building tools to facilitate virtual learning and mentoring, but in the end I found the online format really challenging and draining, so I decided I had to step away. I'd like to replace this work with something else over the course of next year. I'm not sure what yet, but I know I enjoy teaching new developers and have learned a lot about how to do that over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Travel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent February and part of March in the French Antilles, which was a great choice. I rented a big house with a few friends; there were three of us for the whole month and a couple others who joined for less time. We had 6 people there at its busiest! I really love doing trips like this and can't wait to do more once it's safe to travel again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The highlight for me was hiking to the top of Mount Pelée. It was really steep and way above my skill level, but I survived and it was a cool view from the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://kiramclean.com/assets/images/2020-in-review/pelee.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;View from the top of Mount Pelee&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;View from the crater of a volcano, Mount Pelée, Martinique. The little hut is the second refuge on the Aileron trail.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of other highlights, mostly involving beaches. Overall the trip was amazing, except for one week when I got brutally sick with some sort of mystery disease. I took a covid antibody test in the summer which said it was &amp;quot;unlikely&amp;quot; I ever had it, so it was probably something else. A local nurse reckoned maybe just a nasty flu. I'll never know for sure now, but anyway, I also survived that and the rest of the trip was perfect. Lounging around turquoise Caribbean beaches, noshing on French pastries all day, and hanging out with my friends makes for a pretty prefect winter getaway for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously the rest of my plans for the year were dashed, and now I'm just waiting out the pandemic like everyone else. I'm planning on doing some more local trips next year, assuming the pandemic abates enough to allow it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Moving&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I moved again this summer. I move a lot. It was a bit stressful moving during the pandemic, but in the end I got all my stuff here and I really love my new apartment. I gave up my old lease in January before everything got crazy, and honestly I don't know if I would have chosen to move if I knew what was coming, but I'm really happy I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got rid of my car this year so now I walk everywhere or sometimes use Communauto, the car-sharing service here. One of the best things about my new apartment is the location. Everything I need is only a couple minutes walk away. I really love city living. I daydream all the time about moving back to the East Coast, where I'm from. It's so idyllic and peaceful there, but I really don't like &lt;em&gt;needing&lt;/em&gt; to drive literally everywhere. But we'll see. Probably someday. Right now I'm pretty excited to be in Montreal for the post-pandemic years. It was already a really fun city with so many cool things to do before the pandemic, and after this whole mess settles I think it'll only be better. There are millions of cool people with two years or more of pent up creativity and missed celebrations to work through. I'm kind of excited to stick around for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the year I made a few goals for myself. It's the first time I did that but it worked out well, so I think I'll do it again. These were my goals for 2020:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop using Google&lt;/strong&gt;: I did this. I'll probably write a separate post about the tools I'm using now, but in the end it really wasn't as big of a deal as I thought it would be. There are a lot of great services out there that are pretty much a drop in replacement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start blogging&lt;/strong&gt;: I did this, too! I'm not really sure yet what the point is, but I've always enjoyed writing and sharing my thoughts, so I decided to just start blogging instead of continuing to ruminate over &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; to even blog about because I realized I probably would never answer that question. I thought I would write mostly about technical stuff, but it turns out most of the topics that are interesting to me aren't really technical ones. My most popular post was a technical guide, though, so maybe that's a hint I should continue down that road.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn about effective altruism&lt;/strong&gt;: I heard about this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.charityentrepreneurship.com/&quot;&gt;charity entrepreneurship&lt;/a&gt; program late last year and very nearly applied to do it for the summer of 2020. Turns out it would have been postponed anyway, but I've rushed into enough stuff that hasn't worked out in the past that I stopped myself and decided to look into it a bit and decide if I might want to apply for 2021 after learning some more. I also feel like I'm past the age where I can just throw away everything I know and keep starting over. The urge is still strong, but this current iteration of my life is going pretty well so far, and uprooting it all would be a bigger deal than it was when I was 20. &lt;p&gt;Anyway, I did &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/learn/altruism&quot;&gt;Peter Singer's effective altruism course&lt;/a&gt; online as well as a course about evaluating social programs from edX. I learned a lot of really interesting things, but in the end I decided leaving my career in software to pursue charity entrepreneurship isn't the right move for me in 2021. I am thinking about different entrepreneurial projects that would increase my impact that I could merge with my existing career, though. I also did become convinced that I should be donating way more of my big tech paycheques than I was previously. I gave away $8,150 this year and my lifestyle didn't suffer at all. I know this has been a really hard year for a lot of people and I'm not trying to be flippant about that amount of money, but I also know a lot of people who make a lot of money and think they're still not rich enough to be philanthropic, which isn't true. If I can convince some of those people to be more charitable I can have a bigger impact than I can just giving away my own money, so that's why I talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Spirituality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a spiritual director last year, but this year I started doing the Ignatian spiritual exercises with her. I really like having some structure to guide my spiritual journey. Without a schedule to stick to it's really easy for me to go days or longer without really checking in with myself or the divine. I like having a regular meditation/reflection/prayer time as a part of my routine. I'm increasingly finding it helps keep me focused and motivated, which was a literal lifeline this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has become the biggest part of my spiritual life now, but I have still been in touch with several religious communities through the pandemic. I've met a lot of really amazing people with a kind of faith that I find very reasonable, but I still find myself less and less keen to participate in religious organizations the more I experiment with them. I know any organization led by people will have problems, but man the problems in the church are really in a class of their own. I feel like I can't officially join the Christian tribe in good conscience until there's a general movement toward repentance and reconciliation, and I'm not really interested in getting involved as a reformer, which I feel pretty strongly is the only role I could have in a church and not feel like I was betraying my ethics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I'm continuing with the spiritual exercises in my pursuit of transcendence, and I'm keeping an open mind about the possibility of religious community thanks to some very loving and open minded believers I've met online this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Relationships&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In September I got out of a longish, long distance relationship I was trying to make work, and now I'm single for the first time since I was 15. So, basically the first time in my life. This was a really shitty year to have to learn how to be single, but I'm happy with my progress so far. I'm discovering all kinds of things about myself that were either really easy to ignore or just covered up by the fact that I've always shared my life with someone else. I'm really grateful for the relationships I've had, but being alone is a useful experience, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall this year was very hard and dark for me, but I made it! And there were still lots of things that went well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm grateful for my health and that I and everyone I know made it through the year, though I wasn't always sure that would be the case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm lucky to have a great job that I love most of the time and lucky to have great coworkers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I achieved my goals and feel motivated to pick one or two things to slowly chip away at over next year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've found a lot of value in seeking the transcendent, but religion is still very hard for me. The ultimate catch 22. It's simultaneously the richest source of transcendental wisdom and the most unappealing format imaginable to present it in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm hoping next year is better than this one. Stay safe and Happy New Year everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://kiramclean.com/blog/2020-year-in-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kiramclean.com/blog/2020-year-in-review/</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How To Set Up Codecov For a Clojure Deps Project</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: I recently switched to using Github Actions to run my tests because I started getting git auth failures trying to fetch git deps on CircleCI. Learning the random YAML magic required to set up a github action was marginally less awful than faffing with ssh keys on circle. You can see the result in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kiramclean/morphy/commit/6964d1bbe3fd7130e179212f4088cebc753f5aec&quot;&gt;this commit&lt;/a&gt;. The actual steps to set up codecov for your project are the same.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Another update&lt;/strong&gt;: CircleCI's support was extremely helpful working with me to get to the bottom of the issue with git deps and ssh keys and found a solution for me. The problem was that the java library the Clojure cli uses to authenticate &lt;a href=&quot;https://clojure.atlassian.net/browse/TDEPS-91&quot;&gt;couldn't read certain kinds of ssh keys&lt;/a&gt;. I updated my circle config with the solution in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kiramclean/morphy/commit/174e2ffafaaa2db71abcd2a36be11af90963793f&quot;&gt;this commit&lt;/a&gt; and am back to using CircleCI now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently set up code coverage reporting with &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.codecov.io/product/features/&quot;&gt;Codecov&lt;/a&gt; for a Clojure project of mine that uses tools.deps and builds on CircleCI. It turned out to be pretty easy but the documentation for the various parts was a bit ambiguous, so I wrote down the steps here in case you're looking to do the same. You can see all the changes it took together in context in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kiramclean/morphy/commit/c8fd8a425cee712e70ca0ef3fce62b52566ba114&quot;&gt;this commit&lt;/a&gt; where I set it up for my project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Assumptions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These instructions assume your project uses the same specific set of tools as me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clojure with tools.deps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CircleCI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Codecov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same idea should work fine with other combinations of services, but you might have to do things slightly differently or tweak some syntax if you use e.g. Gitlab instead of Github or Travis instead of CircleCI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Set up the project in Codecov&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sign in to Codecov with Github&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &amp;quot;Add New Repository&amp;quot; on the dashboard for your github user/organization (the url should be something like &lt;code&gt;https://codecov.io/gh/&amp;lt;gh-username&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the repo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should leave you at a screen that shows you a Codecov token. If not, click on the &amp;quot;Settings&amp;quot; tab for your project in Codecov to see the token. Copy it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Add the Codecov token to CircleCI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In CircleCI &amp;quot;Project Settings&amp;quot; &amp;gt; &amp;quot;Environment Variables&amp;quot; set &lt;code&gt;CODECOV_TOKEN&lt;/code&gt; to the value copied from above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm assuming your project is already building on CircleCI. If not you can do similar steps to above on Circle (sign in with Github and add your project), and crib my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kiramclean/morphy/blob/main/.circleci/config.yml&quot;&gt;config for a Clojure deps project&lt;/a&gt; to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Generate Codecov reports from test runs in CI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a new alias to your deps project to run tests and generate the Codecov reports using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cloverage/cloverage&quot;&gt;cloverage&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-edn&quot;&gt;:coverage {:extra-paths [&amp;quot;test&amp;quot;]
           :extra-deps {cloverage/cloverage {:mvn/version &amp;quot;1.2.1&amp;quot;}}
           :main-opts [&amp;quot;-m&amp;quot; &amp;quot;cloverage.coverage&amp;quot; &amp;quot;-p&amp;quot; &amp;quot;src&amp;quot; &amp;quot;-s&amp;quot; &amp;quot;test&amp;quot; &amp;quot;--codecov&amp;quot;]}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update your run tests step in your CircleCI config to use this new alias:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;- run:
    name: Run tests
    command: clojure -M:coverage
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. Send the coverage reports to Codecov&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a step in your CircleCI config to send the reports to Codecov:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;- run:
    name: Send test coverage to Codecov
    command: bash &amp;lt;(curl -s https://codecov.io/bash)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Caveats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code coverage isn't a great metric for the quality of your test suite. It's pretty easy to write a couple of tests that exercise most of your code but don't prove much about it's correctness, at least in Clojure where your whole program is basically a pipeline to transform data. I still use this metric though. I find it useful as a high level check to see if there are entirely untested functions, which can also help find dead code. Anyway, just a note of caution to not lean too heavily on code coverage metrics as a measure of the quality of your test suite. It's more like a flag that gets raised if you forget to test something altogether. High code coverage doesn't necessarily indicate a good test suite, but low code coverage definitely indicates a bad one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://kiramclean.com/blog/how-to-set-up-codecov-for-a-clojure-deps-project/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kiramclean.com/blog/how-to-set-up-codecov-for-a-clojure-deps-project/</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How To Set Up Your Own Nextcloud Server</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my goals for 2020 was to stop using Google's products. There are a lot of reasons why, but that's not the point of this post. I found out about Nextcloud last month and it turns out it's a great replacement for a lot of Google. I don't actually use all of its features, but I've migrated my calendar, reminders, contacts, bookmarks, video calls, photos, and news feeds and I'm really happy with it so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of companies that will host Nextcloud for you where you just sign up for an account like anything else, but in case you're interested in hosting Nextcloud for yourself this post is basically a brain dump of how I did that. It took me a while to cobble together all the pieces I needed to get everything working from end to end, so I'm hoping this might save someone else from having to do the same. If you know your way around servers and Nextcloud already you can just skim the headings like a checklist to make sure you don't forget an important step. But if you want a succinct overview of the actual steps I did and commands I ran, each section contains those details. By the end you'll see how I installed Nextcloud on my own server, secured it, set up backups, and set up external storage for my photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some parts are pieced together from other partial guides or longer blog posts, so where relevant the references lead to those sources. This post is more of a quick start with just the essential steps. Anything in &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pointy-brackets&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is meant to be replaced. So the actual command I ran was e.g. &lt;code&gt;adduser kira&lt;/code&gt;, not &lt;code&gt;adduser &amp;lt;name&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What this list assumes you already have&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A domain name. I got mine from &lt;a href=&quot;https://namecheap.com&quot;&gt;Namecheap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An account with a cloud server provider. I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linode.com/choosing-linode/&quot;&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An account with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/b2/cloud-storage.html&quot;&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An account with &lt;a href=&quot;https://healthchecks.io/&quot;&gt;Healthchecks.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your ssh key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$99/year. I pay $5/month for the server I use, $2/month for back ups, $5/year for the domain name ($5.16 actually), and CAD$10/year for carbon offsets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Set up a server running Ubuntu and set up ssh access for yourself&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spin up a new server with your cloud provider. I use a &amp;quot;nanode&amp;quot;, the smallest server available from Linode, with 1GB of RAM and 25GB of storage, which is plenty more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.nextcloud.com/server/16/admin_manual/installation/system_requirements.html#server&quot;&gt;Nextcloud's minimum specs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select an operating system that can install &lt;a href=&quot;https://snapcraft.io/docs/installing-snapd&quot;&gt;snap packages&lt;/a&gt;. I'm using Ubuntu 20.04 (LTS). Nextcloud recommends at least either Ubuntu 18.04 LTS or Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add your ssh key to the server. There should be a way to do this through the UI where you manage your new server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy the IP address of your new server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1.1. ssh into your server as the root user and make yourself a new sudo user that can also ssh into the machine &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/initial-server-setup-with-ubuntu-20-04&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh root@&amp;lt;server-ip-address&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;adduser &amp;lt;name&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;usermod -aG sudo &amp;lt;name&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;rsync --archive --chown=&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;name&amp;gt; ~/.ssh /home/&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close this ssh session and log in as your new user to make sure it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;logout&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh &amp;lt;name&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;server-ip-address&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leave this ssh session open. The rest of the commands below are meant to be run on your server, unless otherwise stated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Point your new server to your custom domain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There should be a way to do this in the admin section for your server. On Linode's there's a &amp;quot;Domains&amp;quot; section in the left admin menu. From there I clicked &amp;quot;Add a Domain&amp;quot; in the top right, then filled in the domain name, my email address, and selected &amp;quot;Insert default records from one of my Linodes&amp;quot; from the &amp;quot;Insert Defaults Records&amp;quot; dropdown, then I selected my new Nextcloud server from the list of Linodes. The steps might be slightly different depending what cloud server provider you're using. By the end you need DNS records pointing your domain name to your Nextcloud server. If you did this through Linode (or whatever you're using), you'll also need to update the nameservers with your domain registar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Set up a basic firewall&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo ufw allow OpenSSH&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo ufw allow https&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo ufw allow http&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo ufw enable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. Install Nextcloud&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo snap install nextcloud&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nextcloud.manual-install &amp;lt;username&amp;gt; &amp;lt;password&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. Set up your domain, enable https, and install an auto-updating certificate from Let's Encrypt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nextcloud.occ config:system:set trusted_domains 1 --value=&amp;lt;your-domain.name&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nextcloud.enable-https lets-encrypt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6. Enable 2FA on your Nextcloud account &lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log in to your new personal cloud at the domain you configured using the username and password you chose above and install the 2FA app
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on your initial in the top right corner of the Nextcloud dashboard and select &amp;quot;Apps&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the left side bar click on &amp;quot;Security&amp;quot;, then search for the &amp;quot;Two-Factor TOTP Provider&amp;quot; app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &amp;quot;Download and enable&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up 2FA with this newly installed app
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on your initial in the top right corner and select &amp;quot;Settings&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the left sidebar, click on &amp;quot;Security&amp;quot; (in the &amp;quot;Personal&amp;quot; section) then check the &amp;quot;Enable TOTP&amp;quot; box and follow the instructions to set up 2FA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to forget my password in the time between installing Nextcloud and trying to log in for the first time. If that happens to you, you can reset it by running &lt;code&gt;sudo nextcloud.occ user:resetpassword &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;* Doing this means you will be required to generate &amp;quot;app passwords&amp;quot; in order to log in to your Nextcloud account in third party apps or other devices (to use Nextcloud to sync your calendar or reminders to your phone, for example.) There's a tiny box with a button that says &amp;quot;Create new app password&amp;quot; at the bottom of the &amp;quot;Security&amp;quot; admin section (under &amp;quot;Personal&amp;quot;, not &amp;quot;Administration&amp;quot;) where you can do that.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;7. Set up backups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.1. Turn on &amp;quot;local&amp;quot; backups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable backups for your whole server for a first layer of backups. I did this when I was setting up my Linode (there was a checkbox in the &amp;quot;Optional Add-ons&amp;quot; section for it). Otherwise there's a &amp;quot;Backups&amp;quot; tab in the admin section where you can turn them on. Linode charges $2/month for this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.2. Set up &amp;quot;offsite&amp;quot; backups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install and set up Backblaze&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a bucket in Backblaze for your backups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make an app key with access to your backup bucket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get the Backblaze cli and configure it
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt install python3-pip&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo pip3 install b2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo b2 authorize_account &amp;lt;keyID&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy the key secret from the app key you just made to authorize the Backblaze cli&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a new user to run the backups and disable password access for it, for security &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kevq.uk/how-to-backup-nextcloud/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo adduser ncbackup&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo usermod -s /sbin/nologin ncbackup&lt;/code&gt; &lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create directories for the backups and logs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo mkdir -p /home/ncbackup/backups/logs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create the backup script and make it runnable &lt;sup&gt;**&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo touch /usr/sbin/ncbackup.sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo chmod +x /usr/sbin/ncbackup.sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo vim /usr/sbin/ncbackup.sh&lt;/code&gt; and copy the contents of the backup script below into your new file, or write your own that accomplishes the same things: &lt;sup&gt;***&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;#!/bin/bash
set -e

DATE=$(date '+%Y-%m-%d')

# Output to a logfile
exec &amp;amp;&amp;gt; /home/ncbackup/backups/logs/${DATE}.txt

# Export all your config and data from Nextcloud
echo &amp;quot;Starting Nextcloud export...&amp;quot;
nextcloud.export
echo &amp;quot;Export complete&amp;quot;

# Compress backed up folder
echo &amp;quot;Compressing backup...&amp;quot;
tar -zcf /home/ncbackup/backups/${DATE}.tar.gz -C /var/snap/nextcloud/common/backups/ .
echo &amp;quot;Nextcloud backup successfully compressed to /home/ncbackup/backups&amp;quot;

# Remove uncompressed backup data
rm -rf /var/snap/nextcloud/common/backups/*

# Remove backups and logs older than 5 days
echo &amp;quot;Removing backups older than 5 days...&amp;quot;
find /home/ncbackup/backups -type f -mtime +5 -delete
find /home/ncbackup/backups/logs -type f -mtime +5 -delete

# Keep 14 days of backups in Backblaze
echo &amp;quot;Uploading to Backblaze...&amp;quot;
b2 sync --keepDays 14 --replaceNewer /home/ncbackup/backups b2://&amp;lt;your-bucket-name&amp;gt;
echo &amp;quot;Nextcloud backup completed successfully&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let the &lt;code&gt;ncbackup&lt;/code&gt; user run the backup script as the root user
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo visudo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy this to the end of the file that opens:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# Allow ncbackup to run script as sudo
ncbackup ALL=(ALL) NOPASSWD: /usr/sbin/ncbackup.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;
  * If you want to undo this for some reason you can run &lt;code&gt;sudo usermod -s /bin/bash ncbackup&lt;/code&gt;
  &lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;
  ** Note this means you will have 6 copies of all your data on your server all the time -- 5 backups and the live versions. The backups are compressed, but it can still add up to a lot of space. Keep an eye on how much storage your server is using. Running it out of space will probably be one of the first issues you run into. I explain how to get notified when that's close to happening at the end.
  &lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;
  *** You don't have to use vim here. Your server probably has nano installed or you can install the editor of your choice. To change the default editor on your server, run &lt;code&gt;sudo update-alternatives --config editor&lt;/code&gt;, and choose the one you want.
  &lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;8. Schedule and monitor your backups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make yourself a healthcheck at &lt;a href=&quot;https://healthchecks.io&quot;&gt;healthchecks.io&lt;/a&gt; and copy the ping url&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo crontab -u ncbackup -e&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy this to the bottom of the file: &lt;code&gt;0 2 * * * sudo /usr/sbin/ncbackup.sh &amp;amp;&amp;amp; curl -fsS -m 10 --retry 5 -o /dev/null &amp;lt;your-ping-url&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will run your backups once per day at 2am (in your server's timezone, probably UTC), but you can set whatever time and frequency you want, just remember to update your healthcheck to match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;9. Test your backups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backups are only useful if you can use them to restore your data. Make sure yours work before you need them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test your entire server backups you can just try restoring the whole server using Linode's (or whoever's) UI. Testing the archived backups we uploaded to Backblaze is a little more involved but you'll be glad you know how to do it when you need it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat steps 1-5, except you can just update the records for your domain that's already set up to point to your new server's IP address(es).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download one of your backups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy the backup onto your new server. Run this in a terminal on your machine (not in an ssh session with a remote server):
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;scp /local/path/to/your/backup/ &amp;lt;user&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;new-server-ip-address&amp;gt;:~&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ssh into your new server for the rest of these commands&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unzip, rename, and move the backup to a place where the Nextcloud snap installation will be able to access it, then make the root user the owner
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;tar -xvzf &amp;lt;backup-name&amp;gt;.tar.gz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo mv &amp;lt;backup-data-dir&amp;gt;/ /var/snap/nextcloud/current/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo chown -R root:root /var/snap/nextcloud/current/&amp;lt;backup-data-dir&amp;gt;/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Import your data
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nextcloud.import /var/snap/nextcloud/current/&amp;lt;backup-data-dir&amp;gt;/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once it's done, clean up the backup archive
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;rm &amp;lt;backup-name&amp;gt;.tar.gz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should be all you need to restore your Nextcloud installation. It might take a while for the DNS records to propagate, so if you want to test that your restored cloud is working in the meantime you can check it directly at its IP address if you add that to the list of trusted domains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nextcloud.occ config:system:set trusted_domains 2 --value=&amp;lt;new-server-ip-address&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note this will only be available over http, so you might get a dramatic warning about security when you visit the ip address directly. To remove the ip address from the list of trusted domains once you're satisfied, run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nextcloud.occ config:system:delete trusted_domains 2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;10. Offset your CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not going to be clear exactly what the environmental impact of your server is, but it won't be nothing. You can get a rough idea how much CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; your server emits with tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.websitecarbon.com/&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;. Then you can buy carbon offsets from a reputable carbon offset vendor, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.less.ca/en-ca/tonnes.cfm&quot;&gt;Less&lt;/a&gt;. I spent $10/year to offset half a tonne of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know carbon offsetting is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidsuzuki.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/purchasing-carbon-offsets-guide-for-canadians.pdf&quot;&gt;long and complicated topic&lt;/a&gt;, and the environmental impact of computing infrastructure goes way beyond CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions, but the point is just to be aware that doing all this stuff on your computer has potentially negative consequences in the real world and to at least try to minimize them where you can and mitigate them where you can't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bonus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Set up a Backblaze bucket as external storage, e.g. for photos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install and enable the &amp;quot;External storage support&amp;quot; app for your Nextcloud instance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &amp;quot;Settings&amp;quot; then, under &amp;quot;Administration&amp;quot; in the left side bar (&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; under &amp;quot;Personal&amp;quot;), click &amp;quot;External storages&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter a name for your new folder&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt; and select &amp;quot;Amazon S3&amp;quot; from the &amp;quot;Add storage&amp;quot; dropdown, then fill in the details for your Backblaze bucket and account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;
* Make sure the name you give the external storage folder isn't already taken. I called mine &quot;Photos&quot;, which already existed in my Nextcloud files, and it conflicted in strange and surprising ways. If you want to call your external storage folder &quot;Photos&quot; make sure to go delete the &quot;Photos&quot; folder that's already there first. 
&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Get notified when you're approaching your storage limit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you choose the cheapest Linode server like I did it doesn't come with much storage, and depending on how much data you have and how many backups you're leaving on the server you might run it out of storage pretty quickly. There's an app called &amp;quot;Quota warning&amp;quot; in the monitoring category you can install to get notified if you're approaching your server's storage limits. You can configure when and how it notifies you in &amp;quot;Additional settings&amp;quot; after it's installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's it! I hope this helps someone avoid hours of searching through documentation, blog posts, and outdated forums. Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discuss this post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25481465&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/kiraemclean/how-to-set-up-your-own-nextcloud-server-2hc3&quot;&gt;Dev.to&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NextCloud/comments/kgdpaw/i_set_up_my_own_nextcloud_instance_as_part_of_my/&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://kiramclean.com/blog/how-to-set-up-your-own-nextcloud-server/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kiramclean.com/blog/how-to-set-up-your-own-nextcloud-server/</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>BarCamp Philly 2020</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I went to a virtual conference this weekend called &lt;a href=&quot;http://2020.barcampphilly.org/&quot;&gt;BarCamp Philly&lt;/a&gt; and had a really good time. The way they ran the conference was new to me. They somehow made the experience feel enjoyable and inspiring, which I thought was really impressive because I've had a hard time getting excited about virtual conferences this year. I've been to a dozen or so since everything got cancelled back in the spring, and this was the first time I stayed until the end and left feeling more energized than drained, fired up with lots of new ideas and inspiration and even a new acquaintance, which is super exciting to me because I find it &lt;em&gt;so hard&lt;/em&gt; to meet new people during a pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is about a few of things that I think helped make this conference so much fun to attend. I think it would be really awesome if there were more events like this. Needing to do everything online makes me sad, but one obvious upside is that is makes a whole world of new experiences accessible. I probably wouldn't have travelled to Philadelphia for this conference, but I got to experience it this year remotely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also want to add a caveat that I am not a conference organizer and am certainly not knocking any other conferences. I have no doubt it takes an incredible amount of work to deliver a conference online, and I'm super grateful for all the amazing people who spent their time (often for free) making all the wonderful conferences I've been to this year happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we're all figuring out how to adapt to this crazy new world and it's just going to take a lot of experimenting and trial and error to land on the best solutions for different types of events. So in the spirit of learning together and optimizing our collective online existence, I wanted to share some things I thought the BarCamp Philly crew did particularly well, and that made my experience as a conference goer so awesome I felt like I couldn't not rave about it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Well Organized Discord Server&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had never really used discord until this year, but it seems to be catching on as a popular platform for groups and events. After seeing the way BarCamp Philly used it, I think it's a pretty ideal platform for virtual conferences. These are some ways they used it that I found particularly clever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Helpful Welcome Messages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With discord it's somehow possible to set up an introduction flow that forces people who are new to the group to see certain information and click buttons to move on to the next steps. I have no idea how it's done, but BarCamp Philly did this and it forced me to read some info about the conference that I'm pretty confident I would have missed if it hadn't been the first (and only) thing visible when I logged in. It simulated the check in experience at a real life conference, which is something I didn't even notice was missing from most other virtual conferences until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a real life conference you don't just materialize in the middle of a lecture hall where someone's about to start talking. You show up, pick up a name tag, check out the schedule and get your bearings, then wander about aimlessly for a little while until the talks start. Maybe you even start awkwardly introducing yourself to strangers or bumping into acquaintances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BarCamp Philly's discord welcome flow approximated this nicely. By the time I had clicked through the whole process I knew what to expect from the day, what talks were happening and when, where to go if I just wanted to socialize or relax, and where to get help if I needed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also had the conference code of conduct prominently featured in this welcome flow, and it was modelled after this &lt;a href=&quot;https://saferspacesnyc.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;safer spaces&lt;/a&gt; one, which was really great to see. I always appreciate seeing these kinds of ground rules explicitly laid out up front, myself being in an unfortunate demographic that seems to attract a disproportionate amount of harassment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Clear Schedule and Sign Posting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the main struggles I've had with a lot of my other virtual conference experience is trouble figuring out where to go at what time. To be fair, this is a struggle at a lot of real life conferences, too. But at BarCamp Philly I always knew exactly where to go at what time and was never surprised I was in the wrong talk. Even though having to awkwardly step out of a room because you accidentally went to the wrong one is a slightly less awkward on zoom, it's still not great, so I was happy to have avoided it all day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had a discord channel for each talk and the channels were grouped by the time the talk was happening, since there were multiple ones in each time slot. At the top of each channel there was a post describing the talk with a useful abstract, links to more info about the speaker, and a list of things to bring or prepare. The next thing in the channel was a fresh zoom link for each session. I really liked how this setup made it super easy to figure out exactly what was happening at what time in which zoom room. That's a lot of stuff to coordinate, especially because there were usually 5 talks happening at the same time! They did an amazing job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Non-conference-talk Spaces&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I loved about the conference discord server was how they set up some spaces that weren't just about the conference talks themselves. A cool thing about discord that a lot of other chatroom type apps don't have is voice and video channels. They're conceptually similar to regular channels, except when you click on one instead of switching the message feed to show only messages from that channel and giving you a text box to type into, you basically are jumping into an ongoing voice or video call, like a zoom room. I found this a little jarring at first, but then I realized everyone is used to people dropping in and out of these rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had a few channels like this set up to simulate the in-between spaces that are everywhere at real conferences. They had a couple of &amp;quot;hallway&amp;quot; rooms, a &amp;quot;quiet space&amp;quot; room, and even an ongoing &amp;quot;crafting area&amp;quot;, where you could literally bring some crafts to work on to take a little break from conferencing and just hang out with people. There was even an after party where a bunch of people stuck around for some drinks and conversation. I thought these spaces were a really great way to bring some of that conference magic to this new virtual space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lots Of Interaction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best parts of real life conferences always happen between and after the talks. I think this is probably the hardest thing to replicate online, which is probably why it feels like it's the main thing missing from virtual conferences this year. BarCamp Philly did an amazing job giving attendees lots of opportunity to interact, which I think contributed a lot to making the day so enjoyable. There were those informal spaces like I just mentioned, but the way they organized the talks also helped a lot with facilitating interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Small-ish Groups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were usually 5 or so talks happening at the same time, so each one had a relatively small group of people attending, like a dozen or two-ish. I really like being in these smaller groups. It sometimes feels kind of pointless being one of a few hundred people on a zoom call. This is different than in real life. If you're one of a few hundred people in a lecture hall, you'll still be sitting next to a smaller group of people you can turn to to chat or discuss the talk. To make that work online you kind of just need to have smaller groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't get the impression the organizers planned any particular group size, but it ended up working out so there were just a few people attending each talk. It's actually possible to have some conversation with like a dozen or so people in the same zoom room, so we had a chance to say a few words before the speaker started and to chat after, which made me feel really nostalgic because it felt pretty close to what it's like in real life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Well timed talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I really appreciated was that the talks only took up about half the time in each time slot. There was tons of time after the speakers finished to ask questions that led to follow up discussions. I love these discussions where you get to hear about what other people think and collectively process the talk. It really makes the message sink in for me. There was also a pretty generous amount of time between each talk, at least 15 mins but sometimes more, which might not sound like a lot I guess but it felt pretty ideal to me. It was enough of a break to make it feel like I wasn't just jumping from one zoom room to the next all day long, but not so long it felt like I wasn't &amp;quot;at&amp;quot; the conference anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Great People&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great speakers and a great community are really what make conferences what they are, and Philadelphia clearly has both in spades. These are, unfortunately, the kinds of things you can't just magic into existence or replicate at just any conference, but I think they're ultimately what made the day so awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Diverse Topics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talks at BarCamp Philly were a total grab bag of miscellaneous interesting things. I really like these kinds of conferences where there's something for everybody. Obviously a lot of conferences have more focused talks just by their nature. It's totally fair to expect mostly technical clojure talks at a clojure conference, for example. But even at special-interest-specific conferences I think there's a lot of value in having a track of more general interest talks for those times where you need a break from diving deep into technical details or want to expand your world a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speakers at BarCamp Philly covered a lot of what I call &amp;quot;intersection&amp;quot; topics – ones that overlap the boundaries of a few different fields. I love these kinds of talks because they attract people from a wide range of backgrounds who all bring interesting and unique perspectives. I got to learn about Wardley maps for mess management (because who doesn't have several ongoing messes to manage?), web accessibility, goal setting, polymath as a legitimate life path, career development, spam, and working from home. I ended the day with tons of recommendations for books, courses, ted talks, and other resources to dive deeper into the things I found interesting and felt inspired to actually do that after the conversations we got to have after the talks. It's been a long time since I felt motivated to do anything, honestly, so this was huge for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Amazing Speakers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One main takeaway for me from this conference is that small, independent creators are where it's at. A lot of the speakers ran their own consultancies or other small businesses and spoke with genuine interest and experience in their thing. I love learning from people who are really into what they're teaching. It makes such a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also something about small-time self-employed people. They're so down to earth and seem to speak more authentically and authoritatively than a lot of hot shot business or tech people you'll hear at bigger conferences. I honestly felt like I did not hear any bullshit all day, which frankly is too rare these days. At a lot of conferences it feels like there are at least a couple flavours of koolaid being sneakily passed around, but I didn't get that vibe at all at BarCamp Philly. It really felt like I was just learning a ton of useful new things from people who legitimately knew what they were talking about. They were even all super keen to talk about their thing after the talks. It was great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new world of online conferences is hard to navigate, and I can only imagine infinitely harder to create. There are some things I think should be ported from real life to online conferences, like showing everyone around, setting some ground rules, and setting up spaces to meet strangers. There are some other things that I think don't translate all that well and should be left behind for virtual conferences, like big lecture halls and big-ego, big-name star speakers. Then there are some completely new things that we need to figure out how to incorporate and use most effectively for virtual conferences, like discord and zoom and remote-friendly games and digital art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my humble opinion, BarCamp Philly struck pretty close to an ideal balance between porting the important things from the traditional conference model, ditching the broken ones, and inventing some completely new ways of running things. I really hope they keep at it and would be super excited to go to more events like this one! This conference will definitely be on my radar now and who knows, maybe it'll be a good excuse to visit Philly someday 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 7 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://kiramclean.com/blog/barcamp-philly-2020/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kiramclean.com/blog/barcamp-philly-2020/</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Christianese For Outsiders</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started hanging in out in religious circles in my late twenties for the first time in my life, I had a lot to learn. Not just about the diversity and depth of different religions, but also about the culture. There are certain words that mean different things in a religious context, and other ones that don't really exist outside of one at all. This a brief overview of some of the language I've picked up over the past few years. These definitions are all based on actual personal experiences from about two dozen different churches/synagogues/groups, so of course as such are entirely anecdotal. This isn't meant to be an academic or universal description of religious terminology, just some new words and ways language is used differently in religious contexts that I found interesting and which might be useful if you ever find yourself in a similar situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Charismatic&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A branch of Christianity that emphasizes physical experiences of the divine. Expression of these experiences can get pretty wild in some churches, ranging from mild swaying, hands up, crying, etc. all the way to rolling around on the floor, running around the room, screaming incomprehensible noises and the like.&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deconstruction&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A process most people raised in a religious household seem to go through where they realize that the religion they were handed as children is probably not true. Many high profile Christian musicians have been public about their &quot;deconstruction&quot;.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Ecumenical&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Usually means &quot;affiliated with multiple churches and/or denominations&quot;. These groups are generally a good place to start if you're new to religion because by their nature they don't have a single dogma everyone must believe to fit in.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Friend&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;With a capital &quot;F&quot;, is what Quakers call fellow Quakers. They may well be lower-case &quot;f&quot; friends as well.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;High/Low&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Depends on the context. Translates to &quot;fancy&quot;/&quot;plain&quot; if you're talking about church buildings, &quot;traditional&quot;/&quot;modern&quot; in the context of church services, and &quot;literal&quot;/&quot;metaphoric&quot; for scripture. &quot;High church&quot; services have things like choirs and robes and golden bibles, &quot;low church&quot; services have guitars and projectors and people wearing sandals. The distinction doesn't cut cleanly across denominations. In my experience it seems to depend entirely on the congregation or just what kind of buildings and resources are available. Regarding scripture, a &quot;high view&quot; usually refers to a belief that it is literally from God and is &lt;em&gt;ipso facto&lt;/em&gt; authoritative and &quot;true&quot;. A &quot;low view&quot; usually means someone is comfortable with the fact that it was written by men in the ancient world and isn't necessarily a snapshot of a moment in history when humans had figured out the way everything should be forever.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Ministry&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Usually refers to work or service someone does that they claim is motivated by their faith or is done in service of their god. Different for Quakers, where it refers to the brief messages that people are moved to deliver during a &quot;meeting for worship&quot; (which is an hour or so of sitting together in silence).&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Reform(ed)&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Depends on whether you're talking about Jews or Christians. Reform Judaism is the progressive version, i.e. where LGBTQ+ folks are welcome and women are equal. Reformed Christianity is decidedly un-progressive, the result of a 16th century backlash against Catholic corruption and hasn't progressed much since (which they talk about as a positive thing). The names kind of say it all. &quot;Reform&quot; Judaism emphasizes the evolving nature of faith and participates in its ever-continuing &lt;em&gt;reform&lt;/em&gt;ing. &quot;Reformed&quot; Christianity, past tense, says the Catholic church was wrong but by God's grace they figured out the one true answer and now just need to stick to it. Westboro Baptist Church is a Reformed church, as an example of where that kind of thinking leads.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Small group/home group/community group/life group/supper group&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Literally a small group of people, usually from the same church, who meet up regularly some time other than Sunday morning. The format varies wildly. Sometimes it's really just a group of friends who share meals, more culty churches seem to use these to indoctrinate newcomers, though. In my experience it's hard to tell what you're going to get beforehand -- tread carefully.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Worship&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Depends on the context. If a Protestant invites you to &quot;worship night&quot; it's a concert; worship means music. If it's a Catholic it may be singing (more likely a choir than a band) but could also be an invitation to kneel in front of the Eucharist (a cracker blessed by a priest which some people believe is Jesus) and pray. If it's a Quaker they're inviting you to sit in silence, probably for a long time, like an hour. Jewish worship usually looks like chanting ancient prayers, but they don't call it that.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Unchurched&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Usually just means &quot;non-religious&quot;, but also used in a semi-perjorative way to refer to other people who are very much &quot;churched&quot; yet believe differently or don't participate in institutional religion as much or in the same way.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://kiramclean.com/blog/christianese-for-outsiders/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kiramclean.com/blog/christianese-for-outsiders/</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Journalism Is Important</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first post in a series on things the 2020 pandemic has taught me. It's been by far the weirdest and hardest thing I've experienced so far in my life. It was a real struggle to figure out how to operate in this new kind of world, but after about half a year I feel like I'm finally starting to get my bearings. Some days feel normal again, and I can mostly do the things I used to enjoy before the pandemic hit. Now that I have some presence of mind back I realized the experience has actually taught me several important things. The first is that journalism is important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We Need Useful and True Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the media we consume now is either clickbait or fake news. Nobody wants to believe that, but it's immediately obvious as soon as you find yourself seeking actual news. You know, like &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; information that's true about the world. This pandemic has taught me a new appreciation for a certain kind of journalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I live in a big city and things around me change frequently and quickly. I don't want to wade through hours of government press conferences or pages of legislation to understand what's going on -- whether I'm allowed to do my plans this weekend, what I need to wear or do in public, where I should avoid spending time. Those are all things I care about and need to know in order to live my life, but the answers aren't immediately clear when there's a torrent of new information coming from every level of government every week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consolidating this deluge of new information into a mass-consumable format is one thing certain types of real journalists do. They have standards and accountability. They have also have mechanisms for earning trust, like fact checking and verifying sources and issuing errata. All of these things make it reasonable for us to believe that what they say is true. At a time when decisions we make can have potentially critical impact, it's important to learn what the latest updates are and be able to trust them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the pandemic I realized the usual places I got my &amp;quot;news&amp;quot; were honestly trash. I started paying several independent media outlets that employ these kinds of journalists -- real people who actually go into the world and collect information then write about it in an honest way -- in the hope that they will continue to do this service and can outlast social media's onslaught on truth and decency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;There Need To Be Consequences For Misinformation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pandemic also made me realize that we really need to do something about bad information. I guess that sounds facetious. Obviously bad information has always been a problem, but we are encountering it in a new way this year and we need to respond to it in a new way, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incentives are completely misaligned right now. Literally billions of people primarily interact with the outside world through social media, which has monetized &amp;quot;engagement&amp;quot;, which is just a polite term for behaviour manipulation. This compels news outlets to produce &amp;quot;engaging&amp;quot; content so they can compete with all of the other content creators trying to capture our attention. Engaging content is the opposite of thoughtful, nuanced content. This is partly how we got to a world where it's near impossible to find out what the facts even are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's crucial that we figure out how to punish rather than reward the current business model of media and social media companies. It should be easiest and most compelling for a normal person to get information from a reputable authority, not some anonymous, personalized, possibly fake source on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the midst of a massive health and economic crisis like the one we're currently living through, peddling government propaganda or disseminating misinformation escalates from being merely annoying and distracting to dangerous and unethical. There are no consequences for this, which is another problem we need to fix. But that's a whole separate series for another time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Support Actual Journalists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don't already, I want to encourage you to pay money to reputable outlets for your news. You can see which ones those are by checking what they published in the early days of the crisis. Find ones who had journalists on the ground, reporting the breaking news as your city was shutting down and rules were changing day by day. We need those people to keep their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertising (meaning, selling our attention) is a broken business model and until we figure out a better way to fund journalism, we'll have to do it ourselves. There are surprisingly few media companies left that still have actual humans on staff, on the ground in a crisis, reporting new information that it's important for people to know. We need to support them to make sure they don't go out of business, having been replaced by clickbait-generating bots and &amp;quot;influencers&amp;quot; who produce vacuous content by the ton for likes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've been blurring the lines between entertainment and journalism for a while now and I think it's finally catching up with us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://kiramclean.com/blog/journalism-is-important/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kiramclean.com/blog/journalism-is-important/</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>An Atheist Tries Religion</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I grew up as an outsider to religion. I never considered it a worthwhile pursuit and spent quite a few years as an outspoken critic. As an adult I began to explore it for myself, and I now have what I would count as a spiritual life. I still find most of what religions teach very hard to believe, but I've also found a lot of value in them. My secular education left me desperately unprepared for the hardships of adulthood and, like many people who turn to religion, when life sent me seeking answers I ended up in church. Spoiler alert: I didn't find any answers, but I did find wisdom and traditions that I now believe have great potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've told my story dozens of times, but I'm sharing it here partially to fill in some details that inevitably get left out when I have three minutes to answer the question &amp;quot;What brought you here?&amp;quot;, and partly as a record for my future self of where I'm at in this moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Negativity and antagonism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's hard to overstate how antagonistic I was toward religion before all this began. I spent my early twenties becoming an enthusiastic disciple of the New Atheists. I read very nearly everything Christopher Hitchens, Sam Harris, and Richard Dawkins ever wrote, watched hundreds of hours of recordings of them eviscerating fundamentalist believers on YouTube, and spent more time than that arguing in their style with actual people -- mostly on the internet but some face to face, mostly strangers but not all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still think they're right about a lot of things, but I realize now that what they criticize is really a caricature of religion. I'll get into what we agree on some other time, but basically where I realized they're wrong is in their wholesale dismissal of faith in all its manifestations. Not all faith is delusional or dangerous. By responding to bad theology with aggressive and contemptuous atheism, we miss out on a world of spiritual pursuits that can be at once enriching, life-giving, and mind-opening. That world is where humanity has found solace and inspiration from the beginning, and it's frankly a waste of time to completely discard it and try to build a suitable secular replacement when we inevitably end up needing solace and inspiration ourselves. I'm now convinced that that world is worth approaching with more nuance, if also some caution and a level head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Meaningful conversations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was 23 I went on a trip to Israel with a few dozen other young people from Jewish backgrounds and for the first time in my life had conversations about religion and god that did not seem absurd to me. Our itinerary included many structured conversations and loads of time to interact and talk informally. Those conversations were my first introduction to some ways of thinking about god that were much harder to dismiss than the notion of a capricious, racist, homophobic megalomaniac in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These people were not arguing over what the creator of the universe wants us to eat or wear, or what kinds of sex we're allowed to have with whom; they were talking about the things that mattered most to me. Things like how to get along with family despite differences, how to build community across cultural divides, how to cope with loss and injustice, and what values should inform the crucial decisions we would be making over the course of the next decade. These were exactly the kinds of things I wanted to talk about, and it turns out the Jewish tradition has a lot to say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Experiencing a holy place&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our trip also included a visit to the Western Wall. I had low expectations but was intrigued by how compelling other people found this place. I wrote my sorrows, hopes, and dreams on a little piece of paper the morning of the visit in preparation, and when we got there I waded into the crowd with the rest of the group. I found it fascinating that people travel from every corner of the earth to touch this wall, and that day was no different. I stood amongst hundreds of my fellow humans, many of whom were clearly having a very emotional time, impressed and slightly unnerved by how freely they expressed what they were experiencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it came my turn to approach the wall, I was struck by how soothing it was to imagine the possibility that something or someone out there cared about the nonsense complaints and requests that were written on my little piece of paper. I found a little crack in the wall to slip the note into, then just stood there for a while. I thought about the millions of people who had stood before me in that same place over thousands of years, giving anonymous expression to their most profound inner commotion. I realized then that I had been missing out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever ways the modern world had messed up religion, there was at least some minuscule piece of it that I wanted. I didn't want to believe that I was just looking at yet another old stone wall. That was a special place, if only for the magnitude of human hardship and desire that had been revealed there. Probably no other location on earth has had such intimate access to the depths of the human psyche. It was like every one of the millions of prayers that had been set free because of that wall still lingered in the air, and I got to add mine to the pile, communing with generations of believers before me in the hope that there's a god out there to hear us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finding community and a faith of my own&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of years later a friend introduced me to a more conventional style of prayer, the kind where you say things out loud with your eyes closed as though you're addressing an actual extra person in the room. I found it extremely uncomfortable and awkward at first, but I immediately felt its benefits, even if it took a while for anything resembling faith to grow out of that initial positive impression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's like believing we're speaking to god and not each other makes it acceptable to express the realest, rawest emotions we have, and simultaneously gives them immunity from criticism. It removes these and many other psychological barriers to being vulnerable and open in the presence of other people. I haven't shared any other experience with people that so quickly helps a group of complete strangers get comfortable with each other, let alone build meaningful relationships. I've since taken up prayer as part of my routine, and do happen to believe that I'm not just talking to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was going through some personal hardship around the same time as all this, the kind of thing that makes you question what you're doing with your life. I was nostalgic for the conversations I had in Israel and in a season of many new beginnings anyway, so I decided to seek a community to explore my spirituality with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't feel capable of belief in the supernatural or physically impossible, so I didn't have high hopes. My suspicions were confirmed that this is in fact a nonstarter in some faith communities, but it turns out it's far from an absolute requirement in many. I found welcoming homes all over the spiritual map in my city, full of other seekers also unsure what to make of some of religion's more absurd truth claims. I'm still somewhat of a spiritual nomad, but I've found home at one point or another in a Reform Jewish synagogue, a community centre kitchen amongst a circle of Quakers, an Ignatian spirituality centre, and most recently with some progressive Protestant Christians on zoom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to be honest about where I'm coming from and pretty much always feel extremely uncomfortable and like a huge fraud when the more worshippy parts of religious services begin, but I've been going to multiple faith-centred meetings every week for about two and a half years now, and have found the benefits of spiritual growth far outweigh the awkward and uncomfortable feelings that come with partaking in religious observances that don't always resonate with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&amp;quot;Spiritual, not religious&amp;quot;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's a cliché I've heard many people use to describe themselves throughout my journey, and so far I think it's also the most accurate description of my own faith. I have a rich prayer life and regularly attend religious services, but I find the structure and dogma of all the religions I've tried so far suffocating rather than satisfying, so I don't feel comfortable yet adopting any individual one as my own. I'm still working through what role I think is appropriate for an organization like a church to have in society and in my life, but I do think at its best religion nurtures a part of us that has been perilously abandoned by secular society. At this point I consider myself a disciple of the Jewish and Christian traditions, having found valuable insights into the art of living in both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another major hurdle I still haven't mentally overcome is the pretty mixed track record of religion. I know now that there's a lot more to it than sociopaths conning the poor into giving up their grocery money and brainwashed followers tearing apart families and livelihoods over tactless obedience to draconian laws. I spent too much time learning about the ugly sides of religion before changing my mind about it, and so far that's still preventing me from just pretending like it's no big deal for them to continue to exist without acknowledging and apologizing for their crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize that that kind of repentance and reconciliation takes time, and I do know many religious groups are undertaking the difficult work of repairing the world. I just wish so many of the reasons it needs repairing weren't their fault in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Figuring out what religion could look like&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all of these hangups, I'm still pursuing spiritual life on my own terms. I've come to accept that it's entirely possible for a given religion to be completely wrong but for a god to exist. I actually realized that when I read the Bible. Scripture is packed with stories about religious people doing it wrong. I'm endlessly bemused by the irony of modern religions that are so blind to their own fallibility yet claim those very stories as their foundation. That's another one of those things I'm still working through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the baggage of religion is too burdensome for me to bear, and I'm unsure of what role that kind of codified spirituality will have in my life in the long run, I'm enjoying my spiritual journey quite a bit. I've found prayer to be uplifting and soothing. I've found groups of other people interested in discussing things I care a lot about. I've appreciated finding ways to spend some of my spare time that don't feel wasteful and meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If nothing else, religion is a brilliant social hack for bringing strangers together and making people comfortable being vulnerable together. I suspect there's more to it than that, but there's a hell of a lot of cruft to cut through to try to find out. My posture toward religion has shifted from purely antagonistic to curious but skeptical, which for me is a pretty dramatic change. It's no secret that the church as we know it is dying. As an outsider it's not hard to see why and honestly hard to have any attitude about it other than &amp;quot;good riddance&amp;quot;. I see a lot of promising signs of growth amidst the ruins of those communities, though, and I'm quite interested in being a part of a new generation of church goers, more focused on faithfulness and spiritual exploration than moralistic legalism and slavish obedience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no idea what that would look like or how we'd get there, but the idea excites me. And I'm pretty sure Jesus would be cool with us exploring new interpretations of ancient traditions along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://kiramclean.com/blog/an-atheist-tries-religion/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kiramclean.com/blog/an-atheist-tries-religion/</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Life You Can Save</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What are our ethical obligations to each other? It's a complicated question. Living in a civilised society implies abiding by a set of shared rules. Some are explicit like laws and contracts, some are implicit like cultural norms, and some are disputed. Whether we have an obligation to care for others, and if so to what extent, often ends up being debated as a political issue, but at its core it's a philosophical question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter Singer's book &amp;quot;The Life You Can Save&amp;quot; addresses the ethical implications of being rich in a world where poverty is rampant from this point of view. It's an uncomfortable topic, at least for me, but an important one. Early in the book he articulates his goal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My aim is to convince you, the individual reader, that you can and should be doing a lot more to help the poor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I share this goal, which is the point of this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Who is rich?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think making Singer's point land with most people will require a check in on the state of the world. I live in Canada, where life is honestly pretty good for most people, and it's easy to forget that an average Canadian lifestyle is exceedingly luxurious from a global perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with an income of $0 per year, a Canadian will have access to world class education and health care, and most likely also clean water, indoor plumbing, a refrigerator, and internet access, which is more than can be said for hundreds of millions people on earth. Earning just minimum wage with full time hours lands a Canadian in the richest 12% of people in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously Canada has loads of problems and I'm not suggesting it should get a pass on any of them. I'm also not suggesting it's easy to be poor in Canada or that we shouldn't be working to alleviate poverty in rich countries. This is just to frame the issue from Singer's perspective, because I think his argument is more salient in the context of &lt;em&gt;global&lt;/em&gt; poverty. Seen through this lens, it's easier to understand it as an emergency that needs our attention, rather than something we can worry about later, or not at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;There is no fundamental difference between us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter Singer's argument is essentially that there is no morally relevant difference between us and people living in poverty in far away places, so there is no justification for not caring about them the same way we care about ourselves and people close to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are millions of people every year who suffer or die from diseases that could have been prevented or treated for as little as a few dollars; things like trachoma, tuberculosis, malaria, measles, among others. Singer points out that we regularly spend thousands or tens of thousands of dollars saving lives in the developed world, then argues that the suffering of people we don't know must matter at least one-thousandth as much as our own, so there is no justification for ignoring their plight. We don't think twice about spending huge amounts of money on medical treatment for ourselves, and we intuitively prioritise such spending above things like eating out or travelling. It's obvious to us that our health matters more than having or doing more things we don't really need, so shouldn't we also prioritise the alleviation of others' suffering above our own wanting non-essential things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a simple argument, but a sound one. Refuting it requires arguing that our own desire for luxury items is more important than the life of a stranger. Most people intuit this as clearly unethical, even without careful consideration of the formal argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We can and should do more to help the poor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having made his argument, Singer spends the rest of the book discussing what it might look like in practice if we followed through with his recommendations. The point I took away from this section is that most people wouldn't have to change their lifestyles much at all to divert an amount of money toward effective organisations that would make a significant difference in the lives of those in need. There are a lot of gains to be had by optimising our existing habits for efficiency. On the topic of malnutrition and food insecurity, he writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world is not running out of food. The problem is that people in high-income countries have found a way to consume four or five times as much food as would be possible if they were to eat the crops we grow directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an argument I've heard before. There is enough food on earth to feed everyone, yet millions still subsist on starvation diets because of inefficiency and waste. Singer presents the data to make a convincing argument that there is some low hanging fruit here that could have a massive impact and save thousands if not millions of lives. We wouldn't have to change our own standard of living, just prioritise efficiency and optimise for maximum social benefit instead of the things we do at the moment, like profit and growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Psychological insights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having made the case for why we should give more and demonstrated that it's possible without much impact to our own lives, let alone unreasonable hardship, Singer discusses the psychology of altruism. There are some interesting ways most people think that both explain why we're so often indifferent to far-away suffering and suggest how we might change that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, many studies show that people give more when they believe others are giving more, so we ought to publicise our giving in order to inspire others to join us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Singer acknowledges that this is difficult. For one, it's sort of taboo to talk about money in most western cultures. People consider financial information, including how much they give, private information. It also appears to contradict the teachings of some ancient and very influential philosophers. Maimonides classifies anonymous giving as the highest form of altruism, and Jesus echos that wisdom in the New Testament. I believe there's something worth paying attention to in both of those traditions, but helping the least among us is a teaching absolutely central to both Judaism and Christianity. If being public about our giving will accomplish that then there's something to reconcile between these two apparently contradictory teachings. That's a topic for another day, but I wanted to flag it here because it's adjacent to other areas I think a lot about. Singer is aware that it's a big ask and is uncomfortable for many people raised in Judeo-Christian societies, but he essentially dismisses this concern, arguing that our discomfort is our own problem and not a justification for selfishness. I have to agree with him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also mentions some other well documented and by now well known phenomena,
like how people give more when they feel a personal connection to the
beneficiaries of their generosity, or how people give more when it's automated
as a monthly withdrawal or fixed percentage of income. These are useful insights
that many charities have applied to influence people to give more, and can be
useful in our own conversations about removing barriers to giving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improving aid&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not many of us are in a position to meaningfully impact government policy, but Singer does discuss some issues with the way foreign aid is currently allocated and spent. It's an interesting lesson in bureaucracy, but ultimately my impression is that there's not a whole lot an average citizen can do, other than campaign and vote for reform in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main issue with aid at the moment appears to be that it's become politicised, like so many other government-run programmes. One example he gives is agricultural subsidies – wealthy farmers in developed nations are regularly subsidised with tax payer money, meaning they can sell their harvest for cheaper than peasant farmers in low income countries. Aid often comes with strings attached, like requiring that the money be spent on these artificially cheap agricultural products, which often must also be delivered by national carriers. In many countries foreign aid is effectively a roundabout way to subsidise national interests, which needless to say is all kinds of inefficient and bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Singer reckons there are large gains to be had in optimising government spending on foreign aid, whilst acknowledging it's an area fraught with political and economic side effects and out of reach for many ordinary people. Regardless, it's worth having on your radar as an issue to consider when choosing who to vote for. De-politicising aid could lead to it being given to the organisations that will do the most good in beneficiary countries, rather than the ones that will deliver the biggest political gains domestically. That would be a huge win, so even though it's a large and complicated goal, it's still one worth pursuing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What would it take to end this emergency?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book wraps up with a realistic plan to implement Singer's recommendations. He makes a compelling case that we could collectively donate enough money to end world poverty without any noticeable impact to our standard of living. He proposes a sliding scale, similar to the progressive tax systems of many developed countries, where the amount one gives is a percentage of total income, albeit with a much higher floor than taxes. For example he suggests someone earning $80,000 per year donate just 1% of their income, or about $65 per month. To find out what the top altruism researchers in the world estimate you should donate in order to have an impact that saves lives, you can enter your own salary into &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelifeyoucansave.org/take-the-pledge/&quot;&gt;their calculator&lt;/a&gt;. The percentage increases with income, but it honestly seems quite reasonable to me. Near the end of the book he argues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ending large-scale extreme poverty would be completely achievable, without imposing hardship on anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's based on some calculations that would have millionaires and billionaires donating large proportions of their income (not necessarily total wealth) and everyone else donating at least a small percentage of their income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm curious what factors other than a simple lack of cash prevent the alleviation of suffering and eradication of world poverty. It appears as though there are enough benevolent billionaires in the world that if it were a simple matter of raising funds, we could have done it by now. I think that's a question worth investigating, but I don't think leaving it unanswered for now takes anything away from Singer's argument that we all can and should be doing at least something to help the poor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He's right that we're living in the midst of an emergency. About 15,000 children die every day from diseases that we can afford to prevent or treat. That would be an intolerable situation if it were happening in our own countries, and once we accept that the anonymity and distance of those people really carries no weight in the decision to do something about their suffering or not, the urgency really starts to sink in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my attempt to cover the main arguments of &amp;quot;The Life You Can Save&amp;quot;, and hopefully to convince you that Peter Singer is right. We should all be donating money to help to end the entirely avoidable suffering of our fellow humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a list of the charities that are most effective at doing that, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.givewell.org/charities/top-charities&quot;&gt;Give
Well&lt;/a&gt;, or the &amp;quot;Best Charities&amp;quot;
list on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelifeyoucansave.org/&quot;&gt;book's own website&lt;/a&gt;. Many of
the top charities are based in the USA or UK, so if you're in Canada like me, you can make tax-advantaged donations to these organisations through &lt;a href=&quot;https://rcforward.org/&quot;&gt;RC Forward&lt;/a&gt; to maximize your impact. For a deeper dive or clarification of anything I wrote about here, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelifeyoucansave.org/the-book/&quot;&gt;book is available for free as an e-book or audiobook&lt;/a&gt;. I'm beginning to evaluate the changes I need to make in my own life, and hope you'll do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 2 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://kiramclean.com/blog/the-life-you-can-save/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kiramclean.com/blog/the-life-you-can-save/</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Why Are Websites So Complicated Now?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I first got into programming because I wanted to make my own websites. Back then
all it took was two files, an &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; and a style sheet. I recently decided
to take up blogging again and started looking around for a simple static site
generator. There are a couple of reasons why I avoided some other approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have had negative experiences with Wordpress that make me not want to use it
again. Plus it is way more sophisticated than I need for a simple place to
publish some thoughts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want unambiguous ownership of my blog. Less important but also relevant, I
want to easily be able to control how it looks. This rules out quite a few
popular batteries-included blogging platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do not want to setup (or pay for) a server somewhere to serve a simple
website with only static pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been writing software for the internet for some years now, but it's been a
while since I worked on anything like what we think of as a normal website. When
I started looking into how those are made these days, I was surprised to find
mostly complicated, bloated frameworks that nearly completely abstract away the
basic task of generating HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn't take multiple new languages, frameworks, or build tools to make a
really simple website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Content is not software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frameworks are for people building sophisticated software that happens to run in
a browser. There is no need for them if all you want to do is put some content
on the internet. I will argue that if your main goal is publishing content you
don't even need JavaScript at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JavaScript frameworks mostly help by allowing us to write non-trivial software
in a language less terrible than JavaScript itself. They can also help with
things like managing state, reacting to user input, and communicating
asynchronously with a server to get new information onto a page without needing
to refresh the whole thing. None of these challenges are present when the main
purpose of a website is to display static information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For that, all we should need is a language to markup our plain words into
something a browser can render, like HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A simple static site generator&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer writing software over configuring software, and I resent things that
are more complicated than they need to be. I'm a minimalist by nature and I am
against the direction our industry is currently headed -- shipping bloated and
buggy software by the ton -- but that's a topic for another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some investigation and frustration trying to do simple things, like edit
canned templates or change the source and structure of my content, I of course
decided to write my own static site generator, like any sane developer would do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now all it does is convert my posts (which I write in markdown) into HTML
and insert that HTML into a template, then put those files in the right place.
As my blog grows I'll add more features, and maybe even make it useful enough
for someone else to use someday. For now it's a simple solution that works on my
machine, and was definitely more enjoyable for me to write than was faffing with
configuring the other tools I tried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A plea for simplicity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get that a lot of people are not making simple websites anymore. There is some
seriously sophisticated software running in browsers now, which I understand is
the reason for the proliferation of JavaScript frameworks and build tools
currently plaguing our work lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people are still simply publishing content to the internet, though, and
we seem to have forgotten what a website is really made of. It's just HTML
(which is supposed to semantically mark up content to describe its &lt;em&gt;meaning
and structure&lt;/em&gt;), and optional styling with CSS (to describe it's
&lt;em&gt;appearance&lt;/em&gt;). These languages are not so complicated to write that we
need complex frameworks that add a dozen more layers between the content and the
final static pages. If all you want is to put some information on the internet,
see if an old fashioned HTML file might be all you need.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 3 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://kiramclean.com/blog/why-are-websites-so-complicated-now/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kiramclean.com/blog/why-are-websites-so-complicated-now/</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Searching for Sunday</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the point of going to church? I ask myself this question weekly. I
didn't grow up going to any sort of regular religious services, but I'm becoming
increasingly religious as an adult. I'm inclined to think that church should be
a part of my faith journey, but mostly because going to church is just what
religious people do. I've never understood the point, and have experienced quite
a mixed bag of emotions venturing in and out of a handful of different faith
communities over the past couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the subject of Rachel Held Evans' book &amp;quot;Searching for Sunday&amp;quot;. It's a
story of her own faith journey and a call to the rest of us on a similar path to
keep searching. I struggle to find the motivation to continue exploring religion
and spending time on faith-related ventures. In a season where I'm wondering
whether religion has any purpose at all, I found this book inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Diversity in the church&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most refreshing things about this book was her sincere exploration of
the diversity of faith traditions. This resonated with me. I've spent the most
time with a Reform Jewish community, but have also been involved to varying
degrees with Baptist, Presbyterian, United, Anglican, generic non-denominational
evangelical, Unitarian, Jesuit, Roman Catholic, and Quaker communities over the
past couple of years, and I'm deeply confused about how we got here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I read about the life of Jesus and what he taught, I hear a call to unity.
And it's not just an empty plea. He teaches us how to get there; we're called to
love the outcast and welcome the stranger. I don't understand how we ever got to
a place where churches have literal rules about who's allowed in and who's not.
It seems to me that there's no bigger obstacle to achieving Jesus' vision for
humanity than the Church itself. He came to condemn legalistic Jews, but instead
of taking that message to heart and focusing on the substance of his teachings,
his followers have just replaced one set of rules for another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel observes this phenomenon, too, and calls us to understand what grace
really is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps we’re afraid that if we move, God might use people and methods we
don’t approve of, that rules will be broken and theologies questioned. Perhaps
we’re afraid that if we get out of the way, this grace thing might get out of
hand. Well, guess what? It already has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's inevitable that we will have differences. But in a community that claims to
revere a man who came here to love and befriend those who were excluded for
their differences, homogeneity should be a warning sign that we're doing it
wrong. I don't just mean ethnic homogeneity, although there's no doubt you'll
have a hard time finding a church with members from more than a couple of
different ethnic backgrounds. I mean that we should find was to embrace
diversity of opinion. Isolating ourselves into sheltered communities divided
along doctrinal lines cannot be the point of spirituality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is spirit like?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another question that fuels my faith journey. I believe there are things
we can experience that aren't attributable to our normal sensory inputs. I call
these spiritual or mystical experiences. Other people use more religious
language, but however you to describe it, spirituality appears to be a
persistent and ubiquitous part of the human experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I experience it as a sense of relentless forward progress, a source of strength
in my darkest moments, a seemingly source-less inspiration to be more generous
and loving, and an outlet for my gratitude when I'm amazed at how beautiful life
can be. Some people call this force/source/motivator God, but there are
literally thousands of traditions and cultures from every corner of the earth
that have similar and genuine descriptions of experiencing something bigger than
themselves. I call it spirit. I find the idea that this phenomenon can be boiled
down to a list of faith statements and church doctrines repulsive. Seeking is
worthwhile. Encoding the results of any one community's search in law is exactly
what Jesus insisted we &lt;em&gt;stop&lt;/em&gt; doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many religions have claimed a monopoly on this phenomenon of spirituality. Some
Christian denominations today insist they know what spirit is like and that it
&lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; matters that everyone else agrees with them. They are so keen on this
that they have been willing to trample the core values of the gospel in order to
spread their ideas about what God is like. From Rachel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems those most likely to miss God’s work in the world are those most
convinced they know exactly what to look for, the ones who expect God to play
by the rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, spirit is at work in the world every day, but we cling to the
past like our lives depend on it for the sake of preserving an approach to
spirituality that Jesus told us is all wrong. In their desperate attempts to
hang on to rules and social constructs that are fundamentally incompatible with
our ever evolving reality, religious communities forsake the very God of love
and mercy who they claim to worship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overcoming cynicism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's probably already transparent, but I'm extremely cynical about religion.
Part of the reason is because I know its truth claims are bullshit and its smug
moral superiority is a sham. Yet something keeps me seeking. For all the
failings of its followers, I think the Jesus movement has a lot to teach us
about things that our world desperately needs to know. Things like love and
reconciliation, acceptance and friendship, grief and pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel talks about what keeps her seeking, and I found this insight inspiring:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cynicism is a powerful anesthetic we use to numb ourselves to pain, but which
also, by its nature, numbs us to truth and joy. Grief is healthy. Even anger
can be healthy. But numbing ourselves with cynicism in an effort to avoid
feeling those things is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of my life this was my approach to religion -- complete rejection as a
result of pure cynicism. It allowed me to get over the anger and frustration I
felt toward religious communities, but it also prevented me from seeing anything
positive at all in them. Letting down that guard has been very hard, and it
still doesn't take much to send me spiralling back to my former indifferent and
contemptuous approach to the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On most days even approaching these topics with an open mind requires me to tap
into my deepest reserves of empathy and mercy. Getting over the cynicism is
hard, but I believe it's the first step toward spiritual growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Continuing the journey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up as an outsider to faith and religious communities. Most of the people
I know are atheists, but they are more Christ-like than any Christian I've met
so far. Their love is sincere and unprejudiced. Strangers and outcasts are
always welcome at their tables. From my perspective, religion has nothing to
offer them, but could definitely learn a bit about love from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder sometimes if this just points to a triumph of those progressive values
Jesus espoused. Maybe our culture has been so steeped in Christian tradition for
so long that some of it has finally started to sink in. Not that we don't have a
long way to go, but I see examples daily of strangers being welcomed with open
arms and communities coming together to lift up the least among them. Isn't that
kind of the whole point?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's hard for a newcomer to understand what the point of church is. All of the
ceremony and expense of running a church just seems obscene most of the time,
not to mention hypocritical. As an outsider, it appears to be nothing more than
a relic of a bygone era -- the last bastion of misogyny and homophobia in a
society that is finally growing out of those harmful attitudes, a stronghold for
regressive politics, a cash cow for manipulative and greedy men to line their
own pockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I realize that these issues have always plagued human institutions. I
wonder how many people before us have had the same struggles with organized
religion but, like me, were incapable of shaking the feeling that there's
&lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; worth paying attention to there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The church as we know it is dying, and I can't help but have any feeling about
it other than &amp;quot;good riddance&amp;quot;. But I don't think our desire for connection with
something beyond ourselves is going anywhere. When I'm honest with myself, I
have to admit that I'm pretty excited to see what emerges from these ruins.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://kiramclean.com/blog/searching-for-sunday/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kiramclean.com/blog/searching-for-sunday/</guid>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>

