<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kira McLean | Ungoogle</title>
    <link>https://kiramclean.com/tags/ungoogle/</link>
    <description>Kira's posts about ungoogle</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 13:08:51 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kiramclean.com/tags/ungoogle/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Morphy v0.0</generator>
    <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      <item>
        <title>What I Use Now Instead Of Google</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I made a goal for myself in January 2020 to stop using Google products by the end of the year. That might sound like way too generous a timeline, but Google owned pretty much all of my data at that point, so it was a fairly large project. Plus I'm a slow and steady kind of person. I know if I give myself a generous enough timeline I can accomplish even things that seem too hard for me at first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;First, Why&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I got into programming about 5 years ago, I kept hearing all these bad things about Google and how horrible of a company it is from other tech people. It always seemed a bit exaggerated to me, but the evidence has been piling up over the years. Learning about &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/google-is-helping-the-pentagon-build-ai-for-drones-1823464533&quot;&gt;their involvement&lt;/a&gt; with the US military's &lt;a href=&quot;https://dodcio.defense.gov/Portals/0/Documents/Project%20Maven%20DSD%20Memo%2020170425.pdf&quot;&gt;Algorithmic Warfare Cross-Functional Team (Project Maven)&lt;/a&gt; was the last straw for me &lt;sup id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href= &quot;https://kiramclean.com/blog/what-i-use-now-instead-of-google/#footnote-1-text&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but even before I learned about that I was pretty uncomfortable with a lot of what I heard. In Google's defence they eventually did &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20210101083904/https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/01/technology/google-pentagon-project-maven.html&quot;&gt;pull out of the project&lt;/a&gt; after &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20201231204850/https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/04/technology/google-letter-ceo-pentagon-project.html&quot;&gt;massive backlash by thousands of employees&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I'm pretty convinced now that their continued existence is a catastrophe not only for public safety, but also for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/recode/2020/1/3/21030688/google-amazon-ai-oil-gas&quot;&gt;the environment&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/01/technology/google-walkout-sexual-harassment.html&quot;&gt;gender equity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.telegraph.co.uk/technology/google/9739039/Googles-tax-avoidance-is-called-capitalism-says-chairman-Eric-Schmidt.html&quot;&gt;the economy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/jgexe8/google-fired-an-engineer-who-wrote-code-telling-googlers-they-had-a-right-to-organize&quot;&gt;fair labour practices&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stallman.org/google.html#surveillance&quot;&gt;privacy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41562-020-00954-0&quot;&gt;journalism&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judiciary.senate.gov/download/epstein-testimony&quot;&gt;democracy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2018/4/3/17168256/google-racism-algorithms-technology&quot;&gt;race relations&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/big-tech-out-of-control-capitalism-and-the-end-of-civilization/&quot;&gt;project of civilization itself&lt;/a&gt;. But anyway, the point of this post isn't to motivate you to also quit Google. I'll tell you how I really feel some other time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of this post is about the tools and services I replaced all the Google things with. I did mostly accomplish my goal, with a few caveats which I describe in the relevant sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Replacements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the short version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GMail → &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/signup&quot;&gt;ProtonMail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chrome → &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/developer/&quot;&gt;Firefox developer edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google search → &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/&quot;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Drive → &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sync.com/&quot;&gt;Sync&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/b2/cloud-storage.html&quot;&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google DNS → &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cloudflare.com/announcing-1111/&quot;&gt;Cloudflare DNS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maps → Apple maps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YouTube → Netflix, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/&quot;&gt;TED talks&lt;/a&gt;, conference archives, and still a little YouTube (anonymously in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/multi-account-containers/&quot;&gt;Firefox container&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Analytics → &lt;a href=&quot;https://usefathom.com/&quot;&gt;Fathom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything else (calendar, reminders, photos, docs, video chat, news feeds) → &lt;a href=&quot;https://nextcloud.com/signup/&quot;&gt;Nextcloud&lt;/a&gt;, running &lt;a href=&quot;https://kiramclean.com/blog/how-to-set-up-your-own-nextcloud-server/&quot;&gt;on my own instance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here's the long version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;GMail → &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/signup&quot;&gt;ProtonMail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ProtonMail has free accounts, but I pay for the lowest level that allows use of a custom domain with it (€48/year) so I don't have to change my email address ever again if I want to switch providers. It was quite a pain to change my email address all over the place, but I started in May and just did it slowly over time. I highly recommend decoupling your email address from your email provider if you're considering switching. First of all an email from a custom domain seems more, not less, serious than a gmail address to most people. But the main reason is just so you don't have to change your email address ever again if (when) you want to switch to some newer, better email provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set up forwarding from my old GMail account to my new email address then filtered my mail for anything sent to the old address. If it was someone or some place I wanted to continue hearing from, I updated my email address with them. If not I unsubscribed. This turned out to be a wonderful opportunity to purge my newsletter and other email subscriptions. Also I'm happy to report most companies are now (finally) respecting unsubscribe requests. Two (looking at you Geektastic and Rakuten) continued to spam me after I requested they stop, so now I filter out all their mail as spam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chrome → Firefox developer edition&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I primarily use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/developer/&quot;&gt;Firefox developer edition&lt;/a&gt; now for my browser, including for work. The developer tools are just as good as Chrome's for the kind of work I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some web apps that literally or effectively only work in Chrome, which ironically perfectly illustrates the impetus for this whole undertaking. For those I use this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Eloston/ungoogled-chromium#downloads&quot;&gt;ungoogled Chromium&lt;/a&gt; browser, installed via homebrew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still have Chrome installed on my computer because I need it for some work things. We use chromedriver for some integration tests and it wasn't trivially easy to trick it into using my Chromium installation instead of looking for Chrome. Replacing chromedriver is a headache, and also not my call to make at work. But it's also not really the point for me. If Google was reduced to a browser that developers can easily launch and control programmatically, I'd be satisfied. I don't use it for anything other than running automated tests at work now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Google search → &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/&quot;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mostly love DuckDuckGo, but there are certain categories of searches where Google returns better results. DuckDuckGo doesn't seem to return many results from forums (like stack overflow or other stack exchange sites), which is where there the answers to a lot of my questions are, unfortunately. So I still use Google Search sometimes, but I do it in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/multi-account-containers/&quot;&gt;Firefox container&lt;/a&gt; without being logged in to a Google account, which at least helps to avoid some of Google's incessant stalking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DuckDuckGo does seem to return better results when the answer is an image, video, or regular web page, which is cool, and I suspect means it would be a perfectly fine replacement for most people. For example this blog is easier to find via DuckDuckGo than Google, which is impressive because I share a name with a small-time TV celebrity who typically dominates search results. We even look sort of similar, it's wild.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Google Drive → &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sync.com/&quot;&gt;Sync&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/b2/cloud-storage.html&quot;&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Sync to make my most used files available anywhere, and I've started moving a huge backlog of documents and notes I don't need to access often but don't want to throw away to Backblaze for longer term storage, just because it's cheaper. So far I just use their web UI to upload things in bulk and browse my files, but I'm looking into ways to do that more efficiently. I really need to de-clutter my digital life. I'm a major hoarder when it comes to digital files. I have scarcely deleted a document in the last 10 years, it's getting a bit ridiculous. But that's a goal for another year 🙂. For now I'm just putting all those files I don't really need to access but don't want to throw away in Backblaze to deal with later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between Sync and Backblaze I got 15GB of free storage, which is plenty for now, though as I move more and more or my scattered files over I'll have to start paying. Backblaze offers some of the cheapest object storage there is, at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DNS → Cloudflare DNS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to use Google's DNS servers (8.8.8.8 and 8.8.4.4), now I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cloudflare.com/announcing-1111/&quot;&gt;Cloudflare's&lt;/a&gt; (1.1.1.1 and 1.0.0.1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Maps, YouTube&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These ones are harder to replace. I use Apple maps now most of the time, but I still use Waze (which was acquired by Google) for directions sometimes if I'm driving somewhere. For media I mostly watch Netflix, but I also watch a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/&quot;&gt;TED talks&lt;/a&gt;. I used to also watch conference videos on YouTube. Now I check conference websites for those, and a lot of them have the recordings, although they're often hosted on YouTube anyway. And I also do still use YouTube sometimes, mostly for home workout videos, but also anonymously in an isolated container.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Analytics → &lt;a href=&quot;https://usefathom.com/&quot;&gt;Fathom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been a while since I used Google Analytics, but I wanted to set up a basic hit counter for this blog and found Fathom. They provide simple privacy-focused analytics that work well enough for me. One really useful feature they have that I consider necessary now is being able to log analytics with a custom domain. Without this, visitors using ad-blockers don't get counted, which most estimates figure is now something like 40% of people, and probably more among tech-type people, like the ones most likely to find this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried Cloudflare's new server-side analytics for a month, but the data didn't make as much sense (it showed the overwhelming number of visits to my homepage, even though the other analytics I had set up showed them going to one post that did well on Hacker News, which makes way more sense). Anyway, the numbers didn't seem to add up. I guess to be fair I &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kiraemclean/status/1340530206516387840&quot;&gt;don't quite understand&lt;/a&gt; how Fathom's numbers add up yet either, but their support has been helpful checking it out with me to try to help me reach some interpretation that makes sense. Fathom's dashboard is really simple, at least, which I like because it's easy to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Calendar, reminders, photos, docs, video chat, news feeds → &lt;a href=&quot;https://nextcloud.com/signup/&quot;&gt;Nextcloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For everything else I use Nextcloud now. I &lt;a href=&quot;https://kiramclean.com/blog/how-to-set-up-your-own-nextcloud-server/&quot;&gt;run my own instance&lt;/a&gt; of it, but there are lots of providers where you can just sign up for a simple account like anything else if you're not an insufferable nerd who enjoys maintaining servers, like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where I have another caveat to mention. I haven't migrated all of my photos off of Google Photos yet because I have about 50,000 of them and it's just a really slow process. I estimated it would take me something like 70 hours to move them all manually, so I'm looking into better ways to do it. I'm confident I can find or maybe build something easier than manually downloading and uploading 50k files in less than 70 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nextcloud does the job of automatically syncing photos from my phone, though, which is all I needed to be able to delete Google Photos from my devices. I'm not sure I'll actually stick with Nextcloud for photos in the long run. The gallery is a bit lacking. It looks like &lt;a href=&quot;https://piwigo.org/get-piwigo&quot;&gt;Piwigo&lt;/a&gt; might be a good alternative. Either way, I'm actually storing my photos in Backblaze, so I'll continue looking around for a different client for a bucket full of photos next year as I work on slowly culling my photos collection and migrating it to a new home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Total Cost&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like I've won a lot by doing all this. I own my data now, so Google can't &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/google-users-locked-out-after-years-2020-10&quot;&gt;arbitrarily take it away from me&lt;/a&gt;, which gives me peace of mind. I'm no longer part of their ad ecosystem, being tracked all around the internet and having my attention sold to the highest bidder. And I also feel good about &amp;quot;voting with my feet&amp;quot;, so to speak. The fewer people use Google's free products, the lower their ability to sustain their unethical business model based on selling mass surveillance data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I also lost some. Specifically a few hundred dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting paid and paying for things in multiple currencies is the bane of my financial existence, but overall the final total comes out to something like CAD$400/year (roughly $300), broken down like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ProtonMail - €48/year (CAD$75)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom domains (for email and my cloud) - $19.74/year (CAD$25)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linode server (for my Nextcloud instance) - $84/year (CAD$105)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carbon offsets - CAD$21/year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fathom analytics - $140/year (CAD$180)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, $140 of the total is for Fathom analytics, which an average person probably doesn't need. Without that it comes closer to about $160, which I think is a fair price to pay for privacy, freedom, and ownership. I'm also not paying anything for storage yet, though, so I expect this to cost more next year once I finally get all my photos and archives migrated to Backblaze or whatever I end up using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should also emphasize it's entirely possible to switch off of Google to free alternatives. All the services I use have free tiers which are quite generous and most likely plenty for an average user. I do think people who can afford to should support independent software companies so they can run sustainable businesses off the money their customers give them and not off ad revenue, but when money is tight there are still lots of options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I got over the initial mental hurdle of expecting everything to be free or as cheap as possible, it seemed totally reasonable to me to pay that much for all I'm getting. What made it click for me is that all those things aren't actually free. Google sells our information and our attention to the highest bidder to generate profit for themselves, then they don't share any of it with us, despite the fact that their entire business model couldn't even exist if we all just refused to fuel it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I'm just dreaming waiting for the day Google realizes the error of its ways and starts running an ethical business, but that doesn't mean it's not worth taking a stand in the meantime. Individually refusing to fuel the databases and algorithms Google profits from is one tiny thing it's totally possible to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: A lot of people in the comments have pointed out that it takes a lot more than this to actually escape Google's reach, which is true. My comment above that I'm &amp;quot;no longer part of Google's ad ecosystem&amp;quot; is an overstatement. As &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25654222#25655515&quot;&gt;one commenter&lt;/a&gt; put it, &amp;quot;Google will still track much of what you do online. The internet is rotten with linked media, amp pages, blogs, and ads hosted on Google servers.&amp;quot; They're right, but that doesn't mean none of this has any impact. I find the de-googling community can be too defeatist and purist at times, but perhaps I swing too far the other direction here. I don't want to minimize the amount of effort it takes to truly become Google-free, but I also want to encourage and inspire average people to make these changes, which requires taking a more pragmatic approach.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discuss this post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25654222&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/kiraemclean/what-i-use-now-instead-of-google-56lf&quot;&gt;Dev.to&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/degoogle/comments/krexp7/i_spent_2020_replacing_all_the_google_things_in/&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small id=&quot;footnote-1-text&quot;&gt;1. That previous link goes to a memo saying that the primary purpose of the project is &amp;quot;to field technology to augment or automate Processing, Exploitation, and Dissemination (PED) for tactical Unmanned Aerial System (UAS)&amp;quot;, which means making AI for drones so they can better target humans and other &amp;quot;targets&amp;quot;. That really bothers me. &lt;a href=&quot;https://kiramclean.com/blog/what-i-use-now-instead-of-google/#footnote-1&quot;&gt;↵&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 5 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://kiramclean.com/blog/what-i-use-now-instead-of-google/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kiramclean.com/blog/what-i-use-now-instead-of-google/</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How To Set Up Your Own Nextcloud Server</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my goals for 2020 was to stop using Google's products. There are a lot of reasons why, but that's not the point of this post. I found out about Nextcloud last month and it turns out it's a great replacement for a lot of Google. I don't actually use all of its features, but I've migrated my calendar, reminders, contacts, bookmarks, video calls, photos, and news feeds and I'm really happy with it so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of companies that will host Nextcloud for you where you just sign up for an account like anything else, but in case you're interested in hosting Nextcloud for yourself this post is basically a brain dump of how I did that. It took me a while to cobble together all the pieces I needed to get everything working from end to end, so I'm hoping this might save someone else from having to do the same. If you know your way around servers and Nextcloud already you can just skim the headings like a checklist to make sure you don't forget an important step. But if you want a succinct overview of the actual steps I did and commands I ran, each section contains those details. By the end you'll see how I installed Nextcloud on my own server, secured it, set up backups, and set up external storage for my photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some parts are pieced together from other partial guides or longer blog posts, so where relevant the references lead to those sources. This post is more of a quick start with just the essential steps. Anything in &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pointy-brackets&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is meant to be replaced. So the actual command I ran was e.g. &lt;code&gt;adduser kira&lt;/code&gt;, not &lt;code&gt;adduser &amp;lt;name&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What this list assumes you already have&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A domain name. I got mine from &lt;a href=&quot;https://namecheap.com&quot;&gt;Namecheap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An account with a cloud server provider. I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linode.com/choosing-linode/&quot;&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An account with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/b2/cloud-storage.html&quot;&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An account with &lt;a href=&quot;https://healthchecks.io/&quot;&gt;Healthchecks.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your ssh key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$99/year. I pay $5/month for the server I use, $2/month for back ups, $5/year for the domain name ($5.16 actually), and CAD$10/year for carbon offsets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Set up a server running Ubuntu and set up ssh access for yourself&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spin up a new server with your cloud provider. I use a &amp;quot;nanode&amp;quot;, the smallest server available from Linode, with 1GB of RAM and 25GB of storage, which is plenty more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.nextcloud.com/server/16/admin_manual/installation/system_requirements.html#server&quot;&gt;Nextcloud's minimum specs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select an operating system that can install &lt;a href=&quot;https://snapcraft.io/docs/installing-snapd&quot;&gt;snap packages&lt;/a&gt;. I'm using Ubuntu 20.04 (LTS). Nextcloud recommends at least either Ubuntu 18.04 LTS or Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add your ssh key to the server. There should be a way to do this through the UI where you manage your new server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy the IP address of your new server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1.1. ssh into your server as the root user and make yourself a new sudo user that can also ssh into the machine &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/initial-server-setup-with-ubuntu-20-04&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh root@&amp;lt;server-ip-address&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;adduser &amp;lt;name&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;usermod -aG sudo &amp;lt;name&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;rsync --archive --chown=&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;name&amp;gt; ~/.ssh /home/&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close this ssh session and log in as your new user to make sure it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;logout&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh &amp;lt;name&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;server-ip-address&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leave this ssh session open. The rest of the commands below are meant to be run on your server, unless otherwise stated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Point your new server to your custom domain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There should be a way to do this in the admin section for your server. On Linode's there's a &amp;quot;Domains&amp;quot; section in the left admin menu. From there I clicked &amp;quot;Add a Domain&amp;quot; in the top right, then filled in the domain name, my email address, and selected &amp;quot;Insert default records from one of my Linodes&amp;quot; from the &amp;quot;Insert Defaults Records&amp;quot; dropdown, then I selected my new Nextcloud server from the list of Linodes. The steps might be slightly different depending what cloud server provider you're using. By the end you need DNS records pointing your domain name to your Nextcloud server. If you did this through Linode (or whatever you're using), you'll also need to update the nameservers with your domain registar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Set up a basic firewall&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo ufw allow OpenSSH&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo ufw allow https&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo ufw allow http&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo ufw enable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. Install Nextcloud&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo snap install nextcloud&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nextcloud.manual-install &amp;lt;username&amp;gt; &amp;lt;password&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. Set up your domain, enable https, and install an auto-updating certificate from Let's Encrypt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nextcloud.occ config:system:set trusted_domains 1 --value=&amp;lt;your-domain.name&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nextcloud.enable-https lets-encrypt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6. Enable 2FA on your Nextcloud account &lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log in to your new personal cloud at the domain you configured using the username and password you chose above and install the 2FA app
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on your initial in the top right corner of the Nextcloud dashboard and select &amp;quot;Apps&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the left side bar click on &amp;quot;Security&amp;quot;, then search for the &amp;quot;Two-Factor TOTP Provider&amp;quot; app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &amp;quot;Download and enable&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up 2FA with this newly installed app
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on your initial in the top right corner and select &amp;quot;Settings&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the left sidebar, click on &amp;quot;Security&amp;quot; (in the &amp;quot;Personal&amp;quot; section) then check the &amp;quot;Enable TOTP&amp;quot; box and follow the instructions to set up 2FA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to forget my password in the time between installing Nextcloud and trying to log in for the first time. If that happens to you, you can reset it by running &lt;code&gt;sudo nextcloud.occ user:resetpassword &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;* Doing this means you will be required to generate &amp;quot;app passwords&amp;quot; in order to log in to your Nextcloud account in third party apps or other devices (to use Nextcloud to sync your calendar or reminders to your phone, for example.) There's a tiny box with a button that says &amp;quot;Create new app password&amp;quot; at the bottom of the &amp;quot;Security&amp;quot; admin section (under &amp;quot;Personal&amp;quot;, not &amp;quot;Administration&amp;quot;) where you can do that.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;7. Set up backups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.1. Turn on &amp;quot;local&amp;quot; backups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable backups for your whole server for a first layer of backups. I did this when I was setting up my Linode (there was a checkbox in the &amp;quot;Optional Add-ons&amp;quot; section for it). Otherwise there's a &amp;quot;Backups&amp;quot; tab in the admin section where you can turn them on. Linode charges $2/month for this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.2. Set up &amp;quot;offsite&amp;quot; backups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install and set up Backblaze&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a bucket in Backblaze for your backups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make an app key with access to your backup bucket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get the Backblaze cli and configure it
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt install python3-pip&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo pip3 install b2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo b2 authorize_account &amp;lt;keyID&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy the key secret from the app key you just made to authorize the Backblaze cli&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a new user to run the backups and disable password access for it, for security &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kevq.uk/how-to-backup-nextcloud/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo adduser ncbackup&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo usermod -s /sbin/nologin ncbackup&lt;/code&gt; &lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create directories for the backups and logs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo mkdir -p /home/ncbackup/backups/logs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create the backup script and make it runnable &lt;sup&gt;**&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo touch /usr/sbin/ncbackup.sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo chmod +x /usr/sbin/ncbackup.sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo vim /usr/sbin/ncbackup.sh&lt;/code&gt; and copy the contents of the backup script below into your new file, or write your own that accomplishes the same things: &lt;sup&gt;***&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;#!/bin/bash
set -e

DATE=$(date '+%Y-%m-%d')

# Output to a logfile
exec &amp;amp;&amp;gt; /home/ncbackup/backups/logs/${DATE}.txt

# Export all your config and data from Nextcloud
echo &amp;quot;Starting Nextcloud export...&amp;quot;
nextcloud.export
echo &amp;quot;Export complete&amp;quot;

# Compress backed up folder
echo &amp;quot;Compressing backup...&amp;quot;
tar -zcf /home/ncbackup/backups/${DATE}.tar.gz -C /var/snap/nextcloud/common/backups/ .
echo &amp;quot;Nextcloud backup successfully compressed to /home/ncbackup/backups&amp;quot;

# Remove uncompressed backup data
rm -rf /var/snap/nextcloud/common/backups/*

# Remove backups and logs older than 5 days
echo &amp;quot;Removing backups older than 5 days...&amp;quot;
find /home/ncbackup/backups -type f -mtime +5 -delete
find /home/ncbackup/backups/logs -type f -mtime +5 -delete

# Keep 14 days of backups in Backblaze
echo &amp;quot;Uploading to Backblaze...&amp;quot;
b2 sync --keepDays 14 --replaceNewer /home/ncbackup/backups b2://&amp;lt;your-bucket-name&amp;gt;
echo &amp;quot;Nextcloud backup completed successfully&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let the &lt;code&gt;ncbackup&lt;/code&gt; user run the backup script as the root user
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo visudo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy this to the end of the file that opens:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# Allow ncbackup to run script as sudo
ncbackup ALL=(ALL) NOPASSWD: /usr/sbin/ncbackup.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;
  * If you want to undo this for some reason you can run &lt;code&gt;sudo usermod -s /bin/bash ncbackup&lt;/code&gt;
  &lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;
  ** Note this means you will have 6 copies of all your data on your server all the time -- 5 backups and the live versions. The backups are compressed, but it can still add up to a lot of space. Keep an eye on how much storage your server is using. Running it out of space will probably be one of the first issues you run into. I explain how to get notified when that's close to happening at the end.
  &lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;
  *** You don't have to use vim here. Your server probably has nano installed or you can install the editor of your choice. To change the default editor on your server, run &lt;code&gt;sudo update-alternatives --config editor&lt;/code&gt;, and choose the one you want.
  &lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;8. Schedule and monitor your backups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make yourself a healthcheck at &lt;a href=&quot;https://healthchecks.io&quot;&gt;healthchecks.io&lt;/a&gt; and copy the ping url&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo crontab -u ncbackup -e&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy this to the bottom of the file: &lt;code&gt;0 2 * * * sudo /usr/sbin/ncbackup.sh &amp;amp;&amp;amp; curl -fsS -m 10 --retry 5 -o /dev/null &amp;lt;your-ping-url&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will run your backups once per day at 2am (in your server's timezone, probably UTC), but you can set whatever time and frequency you want, just remember to update your healthcheck to match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;9. Test your backups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backups are only useful if you can use them to restore your data. Make sure yours work before you need them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test your entire server backups you can just try restoring the whole server using Linode's (or whoever's) UI. Testing the archived backups we uploaded to Backblaze is a little more involved but you'll be glad you know how to do it when you need it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat steps 1-5, except you can just update the records for your domain that's already set up to point to your new server's IP address(es).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download one of your backups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy the backup onto your new server. Run this in a terminal on your machine (not in an ssh session with a remote server):
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;scp /local/path/to/your/backup/ &amp;lt;user&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;new-server-ip-address&amp;gt;:~&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ssh into your new server for the rest of these commands&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unzip, rename, and move the backup to a place where the Nextcloud snap installation will be able to access it, then make the root user the owner
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;tar -xvzf &amp;lt;backup-name&amp;gt;.tar.gz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo mv &amp;lt;backup-data-dir&amp;gt;/ /var/snap/nextcloud/current/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo chown -R root:root /var/snap/nextcloud/current/&amp;lt;backup-data-dir&amp;gt;/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Import your data
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nextcloud.import /var/snap/nextcloud/current/&amp;lt;backup-data-dir&amp;gt;/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once it's done, clean up the backup archive
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;rm &amp;lt;backup-name&amp;gt;.tar.gz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should be all you need to restore your Nextcloud installation. It might take a while for the DNS records to propagate, so if you want to test that your restored cloud is working in the meantime you can check it directly at its IP address if you add that to the list of trusted domains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nextcloud.occ config:system:set trusted_domains 2 --value=&amp;lt;new-server-ip-address&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note this will only be available over http, so you might get a dramatic warning about security when you visit the ip address directly. To remove the ip address from the list of trusted domains once you're satisfied, run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nextcloud.occ config:system:delete trusted_domains 2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;10. Offset your CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not going to be clear exactly what the environmental impact of your server is, but it won't be nothing. You can get a rough idea how much CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; your server emits with tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.websitecarbon.com/&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;. Then you can buy carbon offsets from a reputable carbon offset vendor, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.less.ca/en-ca/tonnes.cfm&quot;&gt;Less&lt;/a&gt;. I spent $10/year to offset half a tonne of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know carbon offsetting is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidsuzuki.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/purchasing-carbon-offsets-guide-for-canadians.pdf&quot;&gt;long and complicated topic&lt;/a&gt;, and the environmental impact of computing infrastructure goes way beyond CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions, but the point is just to be aware that doing all this stuff on your computer has potentially negative consequences in the real world and to at least try to minimize them where you can and mitigate them where you can't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bonus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Set up a Backblaze bucket as external storage, e.g. for photos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install and enable the &amp;quot;External storage support&amp;quot; app for your Nextcloud instance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &amp;quot;Settings&amp;quot; then, under &amp;quot;Administration&amp;quot; in the left side bar (&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; under &amp;quot;Personal&amp;quot;), click &amp;quot;External storages&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter a name for your new folder&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt; and select &amp;quot;Amazon S3&amp;quot; from the &amp;quot;Add storage&amp;quot; dropdown, then fill in the details for your Backblaze bucket and account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;
* Make sure the name you give the external storage folder isn't already taken. I called mine &quot;Photos&quot;, which already existed in my Nextcloud files, and it conflicted in strange and surprising ways. If you want to call your external storage folder &quot;Photos&quot; make sure to go delete the &quot;Photos&quot; folder that's already there first. 
&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Get notified when you're approaching your storage limit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you choose the cheapest Linode server like I did it doesn't come with much storage, and depending on how much data you have and how many backups you're leaving on the server you might run it out of storage pretty quickly. There's an app called &amp;quot;Quota warning&amp;quot; in the monitoring category you can install to get notified if you're approaching your server's storage limits. You can configure when and how it notifies you in &amp;quot;Additional settings&amp;quot; after it's installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's it! I hope this helps someone avoid hours of searching through documentation, blog posts, and outdated forums. Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discuss this post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25481465&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/kiraemclean/how-to-set-up-your-own-nextcloud-server-2hc3&quot;&gt;Dev.to&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NextCloud/comments/kgdpaw/i_set_up_my_own_nextcloud_instance_as_part_of_my/&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://kiramclean.com/blog/how-to-set-up-your-own-nextcloud-server/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kiramclean.com/blog/how-to-set-up-your-own-nextcloud-server/</guid>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
