<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kira McLean | Faith</title>
    <link>https://kiramclean.com/tags/faith/</link>
    <description>Kira's posts about faith</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 08:42:02 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kiramclean.com/tags/faith/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Morphy v0.0</generator>
    <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      <item>
        <title>Christianese For Outsiders</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started hanging in out in religious circles in my late twenties for the first time in my life, I had a lot to learn. Not just about the diversity and depth of different religions, but also about the culture. There are certain words that mean different things in a religious context, and other ones that don't really exist outside of one at all. This a brief overview of some of the language I've picked up over the past few years. These definitions are all based on actual personal experiences from about two dozen different churches/synagogues/groups, so of course as such are entirely anecdotal. This isn't meant to be an academic or universal description of religious terminology, just some new words and ways language is used differently in religious contexts that I found interesting and which might be useful if you ever find yourself in a similar situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Charismatic&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A branch of Christianity that emphasizes physical experiences of the divine. Expression of these experiences can get pretty wild in some churches, ranging from mild swaying, hands up, crying, etc. all the way to rolling around on the floor, running around the room, screaming incomprehensible noises and the like.&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deconstruction&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A process most people raised in a religious household seem to go through where they realize that the religion they were handed as children is probably not true. Many high profile Christian musicians have been public about their &quot;deconstruction&quot;.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Ecumenical&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Usually means &quot;affiliated with multiple churches and/or denominations&quot;. These groups are generally a good place to start if you're new to religion because by their nature they don't have a single dogma everyone must believe to fit in.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Friend&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;With a capital &quot;F&quot;, is what Quakers call fellow Quakers. They may well be lower-case &quot;f&quot; friends as well.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;High/Low&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Depends on the context. Translates to &quot;fancy&quot;/&quot;plain&quot; if you're talking about church buildings, &quot;traditional&quot;/&quot;modern&quot; in the context of church services, and &quot;literal&quot;/&quot;metaphoric&quot; for scripture. &quot;High church&quot; services have things like choirs and robes and golden bibles, &quot;low church&quot; services have guitars and projectors and people wearing sandals. The distinction doesn't cut cleanly across denominations. In my experience it seems to depend entirely on the congregation or just what kind of buildings and resources are available. Regarding scripture, a &quot;high view&quot; usually refers to a belief that it is literally from God and is &lt;em&gt;ipso facto&lt;/em&gt; authoritative and &quot;true&quot;. A &quot;low view&quot; usually means someone is comfortable with the fact that it was written by men in the ancient world and isn't necessarily a snapshot of a moment in history when humans had figured out the way everything should be forever.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Ministry&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Usually refers to work or service someone does that they claim is motivated by their faith or is done in service of their god. Different for Quakers, where it refers to the brief messages that people are moved to deliver during a &quot;meeting for worship&quot; (which is an hour or so of sitting together in silence).&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Reform(ed)&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Depends on whether you're talking about Jews or Christians. Reform Judaism is the progressive version, i.e. where LGBTQ+ folks are welcome and women are equal. Reformed Christianity is decidedly un-progressive, the result of a 16th century backlash against Catholic corruption and hasn't progressed much since (which they talk about as a positive thing). The names kind of say it all. &quot;Reform&quot; Judaism emphasizes the evolving nature of faith and participates in its ever-continuing &lt;em&gt;reform&lt;/em&gt;ing. &quot;Reformed&quot; Christianity, past tense, says the Catholic church was wrong but by God's grace they figured out the one true answer and now just need to stick to it. Westboro Baptist Church is a Reformed church, as an example of where that kind of thinking leads.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Small group/home group/community group/life group/supper group&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Literally a small group of people, usually from the same church, who meet up regularly some time other than Sunday morning. The format varies wildly. Sometimes it's really just a group of friends who share meals, more culty churches seem to use these to indoctrinate newcomers, though. In my experience it's hard to tell what you're going to get beforehand -- tread carefully.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Worship&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Depends on the context. If a Protestant invites you to &quot;worship night&quot; it's a concert; worship means music. If it's a Catholic it may be singing (more likely a choir than a band) but could also be an invitation to kneel in front of the Eucharist (a cracker blessed by a priest which some people believe is Jesus) and pray. If it's a Quaker they're inviting you to sit in silence, probably for a long time, like an hour. Jewish worship usually looks like chanting ancient prayers, but they don't call it that.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Unchurched&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Usually just means &quot;non-religious&quot;, but also used in a semi-perjorative way to refer to other people who are very much &quot;churched&quot; yet believe differently or don't participate in institutional religion as much or in the same way.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://kiramclean.com/blog/christianese-for-outsiders/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kiramclean.com/blog/christianese-for-outsiders/</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>An Atheist Tries Religion</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I grew up as an outsider to religion. I never considered it a worthwhile pursuit and spent quite a few years as an outspoken critic. As an adult I began to explore it for myself, and I now have what I would count as a spiritual life. I still find most of what religions teach very hard to believe, but I've also found a lot of value in them. My secular education left me desperately unprepared for the hardships of adulthood and, like many people who turn to religion, when life sent me seeking answers I ended up in church. Spoiler alert: I didn't find any answers, but I did find wisdom and traditions that I now believe have great potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've told my story dozens of times, but I'm sharing it here partially to fill in some details that inevitably get left out when I have three minutes to answer the question &amp;quot;What brought you here?&amp;quot;, and partly as a record for my future self of where I'm at in this moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Negativity and antagonism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's hard to overstate how antagonistic I was toward religion before all this began. I spent my early twenties becoming an enthusiastic disciple of the New Atheists. I read very nearly everything Christopher Hitchens, Sam Harris, and Richard Dawkins ever wrote, watched hundreds of hours of recordings of them eviscerating fundamentalist believers on YouTube, and spent more time than that arguing in their style with actual people -- mostly on the internet but some face to face, mostly strangers but not all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still think they're right about a lot of things, but I realize now that what they criticize is really a caricature of religion. I'll get into what we agree on some other time, but basically where I realized they're wrong is in their wholesale dismissal of faith in all its manifestations. Not all faith is delusional or dangerous. By responding to bad theology with aggressive and contemptuous atheism, we miss out on a world of spiritual pursuits that can be at once enriching, life-giving, and mind-opening. That world is where humanity has found solace and inspiration from the beginning, and it's frankly a waste of time to completely discard it and try to build a suitable secular replacement when we inevitably end up needing solace and inspiration ourselves. I'm now convinced that that world is worth approaching with more nuance, if also some caution and a level head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Meaningful conversations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was 23 I went on a trip to Israel with a few dozen other young people from Jewish backgrounds and for the first time in my life had conversations about religion and god that did not seem absurd to me. Our itinerary included many structured conversations and loads of time to interact and talk informally. Those conversations were my first introduction to some ways of thinking about god that were much harder to dismiss than the notion of a capricious, racist, homophobic megalomaniac in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These people were not arguing over what the creator of the universe wants us to eat or wear, or what kinds of sex we're allowed to have with whom; they were talking about the things that mattered most to me. Things like how to get along with family despite differences, how to build community across cultural divides, how to cope with loss and injustice, and what values should inform the crucial decisions we would be making over the course of the next decade. These were exactly the kinds of things I wanted to talk about, and it turns out the Jewish tradition has a lot to say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Experiencing a holy place&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our trip also included a visit to the Western Wall. I had low expectations but was intrigued by how compelling other people found this place. I wrote my sorrows, hopes, and dreams on a little piece of paper the morning of the visit in preparation, and when we got there I waded into the crowd with the rest of the group. I found it fascinating that people travel from every corner of the earth to touch this wall, and that day was no different. I stood amongst hundreds of my fellow humans, many of whom were clearly having a very emotional time, impressed and slightly unnerved by how freely they expressed what they were experiencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it came my turn to approach the wall, I was struck by how soothing it was to imagine the possibility that something or someone out there cared about the nonsense complaints and requests that were written on my little piece of paper. I found a little crack in the wall to slip the note into, then just stood there for a while. I thought about the millions of people who had stood before me in that same place over thousands of years, giving anonymous expression to their most profound inner commotion. I realized then that I had been missing out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever ways the modern world had messed up religion, there was at least some minuscule piece of it that I wanted. I didn't want to believe that I was just looking at yet another old stone wall. That was a special place, if only for the magnitude of human hardship and desire that had been revealed there. Probably no other location on earth has had such intimate access to the depths of the human psyche. It was like every one of the millions of prayers that had been set free because of that wall still lingered in the air, and I got to add mine to the pile, communing with generations of believers before me in the hope that there's a god out there to hear us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finding community and a faith of my own&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of years later a friend introduced me to a more conventional style of prayer, the kind where you say things out loud with your eyes closed as though you're addressing an actual extra person in the room. I found it extremely uncomfortable and awkward at first, but I immediately felt its benefits, even if it took a while for anything resembling faith to grow out of that initial positive impression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's like believing we're speaking to god and not each other makes it acceptable to express the realest, rawest emotions we have, and simultaneously gives them immunity from criticism. It removes these and many other psychological barriers to being vulnerable and open in the presence of other people. I haven't shared any other experience with people that so quickly helps a group of complete strangers get comfortable with each other, let alone build meaningful relationships. I've since taken up prayer as part of my routine, and do happen to believe that I'm not just talking to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was going through some personal hardship around the same time as all this, the kind of thing that makes you question what you're doing with your life. I was nostalgic for the conversations I had in Israel and in a season of many new beginnings anyway, so I decided to seek a community to explore my spirituality with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't feel capable of belief in the supernatural or physically impossible, so I didn't have high hopes. My suspicions were confirmed that this is in fact a nonstarter in some faith communities, but it turns out it's far from an absolute requirement in many. I found welcoming homes all over the spiritual map in my city, full of other seekers also unsure what to make of some of religion's more absurd truth claims. I'm still somewhat of a spiritual nomad, but I've found home at one point or another in a Reform Jewish synagogue, a community centre kitchen amongst a circle of Quakers, an Ignatian spirituality centre, and most recently with some progressive Protestant Christians on zoom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to be honest about where I'm coming from and pretty much always feel extremely uncomfortable and like a huge fraud when the more worshippy parts of religious services begin, but I've been going to multiple faith-centred meetings every week for about two and a half years now, and have found the benefits of spiritual growth far outweigh the awkward and uncomfortable feelings that come with partaking in religious observances that don't always resonate with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&amp;quot;Spiritual, not religious&amp;quot;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's a cliché I've heard many people use to describe themselves throughout my journey, and so far I think it's also the most accurate description of my own faith. I have a rich prayer life and regularly attend religious services, but I find the structure and dogma of all the religions I've tried so far suffocating rather than satisfying, so I don't feel comfortable yet adopting any individual one as my own. I'm still working through what role I think is appropriate for an organization like a church to have in society and in my life, but I do think at its best religion nurtures a part of us that has been perilously abandoned by secular society. At this point I consider myself a disciple of the Jewish and Christian traditions, having found valuable insights into the art of living in both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another major hurdle I still haven't mentally overcome is the pretty mixed track record of religion. I know now that there's a lot more to it than sociopaths conning the poor into giving up their grocery money and brainwashed followers tearing apart families and livelihoods over tactless obedience to draconian laws. I spent too much time learning about the ugly sides of religion before changing my mind about it, and so far that's still preventing me from just pretending like it's no big deal for them to continue to exist without acknowledging and apologizing for their crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize that that kind of repentance and reconciliation takes time, and I do know many religious groups are undertaking the difficult work of repairing the world. I just wish so many of the reasons it needs repairing weren't their fault in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Figuring out what religion could look like&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all of these hangups, I'm still pursuing spiritual life on my own terms. I've come to accept that it's entirely possible for a given religion to be completely wrong but for a god to exist. I actually realized that when I read the Bible. Scripture is packed with stories about religious people doing it wrong. I'm endlessly bemused by the irony of modern religions that are so blind to their own fallibility yet claim those very stories as their foundation. That's another one of those things I'm still working through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the baggage of religion is too burdensome for me to bear, and I'm unsure of what role that kind of codified spirituality will have in my life in the long run, I'm enjoying my spiritual journey quite a bit. I've found prayer to be uplifting and soothing. I've found groups of other people interested in discussing things I care a lot about. I've appreciated finding ways to spend some of my spare time that don't feel wasteful and meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If nothing else, religion is a brilliant social hack for bringing strangers together and making people comfortable being vulnerable together. I suspect there's more to it than that, but there's a hell of a lot of cruft to cut through to try to find out. My posture toward religion has shifted from purely antagonistic to curious but skeptical, which for me is a pretty dramatic change. It's no secret that the church as we know it is dying. As an outsider it's not hard to see why and honestly hard to have any attitude about it other than &amp;quot;good riddance&amp;quot;. I see a lot of promising signs of growth amidst the ruins of those communities, though, and I'm quite interested in being a part of a new generation of church goers, more focused on faithfulness and spiritual exploration than moralistic legalism and slavish obedience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no idea what that would look like or how we'd get there, but the idea excites me. And I'm pretty sure Jesus would be cool with us exploring new interpretations of ancient traditions along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://kiramclean.com/blog/an-atheist-tries-religion/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kiramclean.com/blog/an-atheist-tries-religion/</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Searching for Sunday</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the point of going to church? I ask myself this question weekly. I
didn't grow up going to any sort of regular religious services, but I'm becoming
increasingly religious as an adult. I'm inclined to think that church should be
a part of my faith journey, but mostly because going to church is just what
religious people do. I've never understood the point, and have experienced quite
a mixed bag of emotions venturing in and out of a handful of different faith
communities over the past couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the subject of Rachel Held Evans' book &amp;quot;Searching for Sunday&amp;quot;. It's a
story of her own faith journey and a call to the rest of us on a similar path to
keep searching. I struggle to find the motivation to continue exploring religion
and spending time on faith-related ventures. In a season where I'm wondering
whether religion has any purpose at all, I found this book inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Diversity in the church&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most refreshing things about this book was her sincere exploration of
the diversity of faith traditions. This resonated with me. I've spent the most
time with a Reform Jewish community, but have also been involved to varying
degrees with Baptist, Presbyterian, United, Anglican, generic non-denominational
evangelical, Unitarian, Jesuit, Roman Catholic, and Quaker communities over the
past couple of years, and I'm deeply confused about how we got here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I read about the life of Jesus and what he taught, I hear a call to unity.
And it's not just an empty plea. He teaches us how to get there; we're called to
love the outcast and welcome the stranger. I don't understand how we ever got to
a place where churches have literal rules about who's allowed in and who's not.
It seems to me that there's no bigger obstacle to achieving Jesus' vision for
humanity than the Church itself. He came to condemn legalistic Jews, but instead
of taking that message to heart and focusing on the substance of his teachings,
his followers have just replaced one set of rules for another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel observes this phenomenon, too, and calls us to understand what grace
really is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps we’re afraid that if we move, God might use people and methods we
don’t approve of, that rules will be broken and theologies questioned. Perhaps
we’re afraid that if we get out of the way, this grace thing might get out of
hand. Well, guess what? It already has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's inevitable that we will have differences. But in a community that claims to
revere a man who came here to love and befriend those who were excluded for
their differences, homogeneity should be a warning sign that we're doing it
wrong. I don't just mean ethnic homogeneity, although there's no doubt you'll
have a hard time finding a church with members from more than a couple of
different ethnic backgrounds. I mean that we should find was to embrace
diversity of opinion. Isolating ourselves into sheltered communities divided
along doctrinal lines cannot be the point of spirituality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is spirit like?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another question that fuels my faith journey. I believe there are things
we can experience that aren't attributable to our normal sensory inputs. I call
these spiritual or mystical experiences. Other people use more religious
language, but however you to describe it, spirituality appears to be a
persistent and ubiquitous part of the human experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I experience it as a sense of relentless forward progress, a source of strength
in my darkest moments, a seemingly source-less inspiration to be more generous
and loving, and an outlet for my gratitude when I'm amazed at how beautiful life
can be. Some people call this force/source/motivator God, but there are
literally thousands of traditions and cultures from every corner of the earth
that have similar and genuine descriptions of experiencing something bigger than
themselves. I call it spirit. I find the idea that this phenomenon can be boiled
down to a list of faith statements and church doctrines repulsive. Seeking is
worthwhile. Encoding the results of any one community's search in law is exactly
what Jesus insisted we &lt;em&gt;stop&lt;/em&gt; doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many religions have claimed a monopoly on this phenomenon of spirituality. Some
Christian denominations today insist they know what spirit is like and that it
&lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; matters that everyone else agrees with them. They are so keen on this
that they have been willing to trample the core values of the gospel in order to
spread their ideas about what God is like. From Rachel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems those most likely to miss God’s work in the world are those most
convinced they know exactly what to look for, the ones who expect God to play
by the rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, spirit is at work in the world every day, but we cling to the
past like our lives depend on it for the sake of preserving an approach to
spirituality that Jesus told us is all wrong. In their desperate attempts to
hang on to rules and social constructs that are fundamentally incompatible with
our ever evolving reality, religious communities forsake the very God of love
and mercy who they claim to worship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overcoming cynicism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's probably already transparent, but I'm extremely cynical about religion.
Part of the reason is because I know its truth claims are bullshit and its smug
moral superiority is a sham. Yet something keeps me seeking. For all the
failings of its followers, I think the Jesus movement has a lot to teach us
about things that our world desperately needs to know. Things like love and
reconciliation, acceptance and friendship, grief and pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel talks about what keeps her seeking, and I found this insight inspiring:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cynicism is a powerful anesthetic we use to numb ourselves to pain, but which
also, by its nature, numbs us to truth and joy. Grief is healthy. Even anger
can be healthy. But numbing ourselves with cynicism in an effort to avoid
feeling those things is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of my life this was my approach to religion -- complete rejection as a
result of pure cynicism. It allowed me to get over the anger and frustration I
felt toward religious communities, but it also prevented me from seeing anything
positive at all in them. Letting down that guard has been very hard, and it
still doesn't take much to send me spiralling back to my former indifferent and
contemptuous approach to the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On most days even approaching these topics with an open mind requires me to tap
into my deepest reserves of empathy and mercy. Getting over the cynicism is
hard, but I believe it's the first step toward spiritual growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Continuing the journey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up as an outsider to faith and religious communities. Most of the people
I know are atheists, but they are more Christ-like than any Christian I've met
so far. Their love is sincere and unprejudiced. Strangers and outcasts are
always welcome at their tables. From my perspective, religion has nothing to
offer them, but could definitely learn a bit about love from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder sometimes if this just points to a triumph of those progressive values
Jesus espoused. Maybe our culture has been so steeped in Christian tradition for
so long that some of it has finally started to sink in. Not that we don't have a
long way to go, but I see examples daily of strangers being welcomed with open
arms and communities coming together to lift up the least among them. Isn't that
kind of the whole point?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's hard for a newcomer to understand what the point of church is. All of the
ceremony and expense of running a church just seems obscene most of the time,
not to mention hypocritical. As an outsider, it appears to be nothing more than
a relic of a bygone era -- the last bastion of misogyny and homophobia in a
society that is finally growing out of those harmful attitudes, a stronghold for
regressive politics, a cash cow for manipulative and greedy men to line their
own pockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I realize that these issues have always plagued human institutions. I
wonder how many people before us have had the same struggles with organized
religion but, like me, were incapable of shaking the feeling that there's
&lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; worth paying attention to there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The church as we know it is dying, and I can't help but have any feeling about
it other than &amp;quot;good riddance&amp;quot;. But I don't think our desire for connection with
something beyond ourselves is going anywhere. When I'm honest with myself, I
have to admit that I'm pretty excited to see what emerges from these ruins.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://kiramclean.com/blog/searching-for-sunday/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kiramclean.com/blog/searching-for-sunday/</guid>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
